<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">132</field>
<field name="content">Erenumab in chronic migraine with medication overuse: Subgroup analysis of a randomized trial.,&quot;To describe the process of establishing a selective laser trabeculoplasty (SLT) service delivered by experienced allied health professionals (AHP) in a Scottish NHS Hospital Eye Service, and assess the safety and efficacy in comparison with SLT performed by ophthalmologists. A training scheme for AHPs who were experienced in extended roles within the glaucoma service was developed, consisting of supervised training by a consultant ophthalmologist specialising in glaucoma leading to the AHPs independently delivering SLT. A prospective audit of consecutive SLT procedures performed by AHPs between November 2015 and April 2017 was performed. Data were analysed and compared to a previous intradepartmental audit of SLT performed by ophthalmologists (consultants and trainees). A total of 325 eyes of 208 patients underwent SLT, of which 117 patients had bilateral SLT in a single session. The overall rate of complications was 3.9%, however these were minor and/or self-limiting (this compared to a 3.8% complication rate in the ophthalmologist delivered SLT series). The rate of intraocular pressure (IOP) spike was 0.3%, compared to 1.4% in the ophthalmologist delivered SLT series. Mean IOP at listing was 20.95.1mmHg, 17.34.5mmHg at 3months post SLT and 17.63.7mmHg at 12months-a median reduction of 16.7% at 3months and 17.4% at 12months. There was no statistically significant difference between the percentage reduction in IOP in the AHP and ophthalmologist delivered SLT groups at 3 or 12months. This is the first service of its kind in Scotland and the outcomes of this study demonstrate that the AHP delivered SLT service is at least as safe as the previous ophthalmologist delivered SLT service. The data demonstrate a similar efficacy between AHP and ophthalmologist delivered SLT. In the face of increasing demand and workload, this is a practical model in service commissioning to free up medical clinicians for more complex glaucoma management. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>