<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">162</field>
<field name="content">Teleophthalmology Screening for Diabetic Retinopathy in Brazil: Applicability and Economic Assessment.,&quot;To test a model of integrated pediatric eye care delivery and examine the prevalence and factors associated with childhood ocular morbidity in a peri-urban setting in Bangladesh. Cross-sectional, population-based study. The study was conducted in three phases among children aged 15 years. Trained community health workers (CHWs) conducted awareness intervention and identified children with ocular problems. These children were then referred to the base hospital for examination and treatment by ophthalmologists. A pediatric ophthalmologist further examined the children with complicated eye diseases and ensured treatment at a tertiary public eye hospital. Awareness, referral patterns, and health-seeking behavior were also examined. All data were analyzed statistically using Statistical Package for Social Sciences. CHWs screened 33,549 eligible children and identified 1887 cases with ocular morbidity. The prevalence of ocular morbidity and childhood blindness were 5.63% (95% confidence interval [CI] = 5.27-6.16) and 0.060% (95% CI = 0.03-0.11), respectively. The most commonly observed ocular morbidities were refractive error (3.24%; 95% CI = 3.11-3.45), allergic eye conditions (1.2%; 95% = CI 0.74-1.27), and nasolacrimal duct obstruction (0.52%; 95% CI = 0.25-0.74). Blindness was more frequently seen in children aged &lt;5 years than in those aged 5-15 years (&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=7.25; P=0.007). The causes of blindness were corneal opacity, congenital eye anomaly, cataract, retinopathy of prematurity, and retinoblastoma. The prevalence of ocular morbidity was higher among older children, boys, children with low parental education and income, and children from households dwelling in slums. This study demonstrated that in a setting where screening and treatment for vision problems remain low, ocular morbidity among children could be easily identified through well-designed community-based screening programs involving appropriately trained CHWs. Community mobilization, awareness, and early detection of childhood eye diseases, with effective referral mechanisms for accessing appropriate care, are crucially important to improve service delivery. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>