<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">171</field>
<field name="content">Mouse Extraocular Muscles and the Musculotopic Organization of their Innervation.,&quot;Aflibercept and ranibizumab are novel drugs for effectively treating wet age-associated macular degeneration (AMD). In the present study, the effect of aflibercept and ranibizumab on wet AMD was compared. A total of 80 AMD patients were intravitreously treated with aflibercept (2.0 mg/dose, 40 participants) or ranibizumab (0.3 mg/dose, 40 participants). The mean visual acuity and central subfield thickness (CTS) were determined at baseline and each follow-up visit (every 4 weeks). ELISA was used to detect the expression of transforming growth factor-1 (TGF-1), monocyte chemoattractant protein 1 (MCP-1) and interleukin 6 (IL-6). The primary outcome was the mean change in visual acuity letter score (VAS) and CTS at 1 year. The VAS was markedly improved by 13.1 in the aflibercept group and by 11.0 in the ranibizumab group. In a subgroup of patients with an initial VAS of &lt;69, the mean improvement in the VAS was 17.7 in the aflibercept group and 13.2 in the ranibizumab group (P&lt;0.01). The mean CTS was markedly decreased by 141 in the aflibercept group and by 134 in the ranibizumab group. In the subgroup of patients with an initial VAS of &lt;69, the mean CTS was decreased by 171 in the aflibercept group and by 154 in the ranibizumab group (P&lt;0.01). However, the change of VAS and CTS was similar between the ranibizumab and aflibercept groups when the initial VAS was 69. No significant differences in serious adverse events were identified between the aflibercept and ranibizumab groups. The levels of TGF-1, IL-6 and MCP-1 were decreased by the aflibercept and ranibizumab treatments. The decrease in the levels of the inflammatory factors was more obvious in patients with an initial VAS of &lt;69 in comparison with that in patients with an initial VAS of 69. Negative correlations between the levels of TGF-1, MCP-1 and IL-6 and the mean change of VAS when patients were treated with aflibercept or ranibizumab were identified among all ages. Positive correlations between the levels of TGF-1, MCP-1 and IL-6 and the mean change of CTS were observed when the initial VAS of the patients was &lt;69. In conclusion, the efficacy of aflibercept in treating patients with AMD was better than that of ranibizumab when the initial VAS of the patients was &lt;69. The inhibition of inflammatory factors may be a secondary effect of aflibercept and ranibizumab treatment. The present study provides a useful reference for the clinical treatment of wet AMD (Chinese Clinical Trial Registry no. ChiCTR1800017782). &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>