<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">174</field>
<field name="content">PACAP Attenuates Optic Nerve Crush-Induced Retinal Ganglion Cell Apoptosis Via Activation of the CREB-Bcl-2 Pathway.,&quot;Esophageal cancer (EC) is one of the malignant tumors with a poor prognosis. The early stage of EC is asymptomatic, so identification of cancer biomarkers is important for early detection and clinical practice. In this study, we compared the protein expression profiles in esophageal squamous cell carcinoma (ESCC) tissues and adjacent normal esophageal tissues from five patients through high-resolution label-free mass spectrometry. Through bioinformatics analysis, we found the differentially expressed proteins of ESCC. To perform the rapid identification of biomarkers, we adopted a high-throughput protein identification technique of Quantitative Dot Blot (QDB). Meanwhile, the QDB results were verified by classical immunohistochemistry. In total 2297 proteins were identified, out of which 308 proteins were differentially expressed between ESCC tissues and normal tissues. By bioinformatics analysis, the four up-regulated proteins (PTMA, PAK2, PPP1CA, HMGB2) and the five down-regulated proteins (Caveolin, Integrin beta-1, Collagen alpha-2(VI), Leiomodin-1 and Vinculin) were selected and validated in ESCC by Western Blot. Furthermore, we performed the QDB and IHC analysis in 64 patients and 117 patients, respectively. The PTMA expression was up-regulated gradually along the progression of ESCC, and the PTMA expression ratio between tumor and adjacent normal tissue was significantly increased along with the progression. Therefore, we suggest that PTMA might be a potential candidate biomarker for ESCC. In this study, label-free quantitative proteomics combined with QDB revealed that PTMA expression was up-regulated in ESCC tissues, and PTMA might be a potential candidate for ESCC. Since Western Blot cannot achieve rapid and high-throughput screening of mass spectrometry results, the emergence of QDB meets this demand and provides an effective method for the identification of biomarkers. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>