<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">177</field>
<field name="content">Genome-wide meta-analysis identifies multiple novel loci associated with serum uric acid levels in Japanese individuals.,&quot;The mammalian CNS is capable of tolerating chronic hypoxia, but cell type-specific responses to this stress have not been systematically characterized. In the Norrin KO (&lt;i&gt;Ndp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;\n                        &lt;i&gt;KO&lt;/i&gt;\n                    &lt;/sup&gt; ) mouse, a model of familial exudative vitreoretinopathy (FEVR), developmental hypovascularization of the retina produces chronic hypoxia of inner nuclear-layer (INL) neurons and Muller glia. We used single-cell RNA sequencing, untargeted metabolomics, and metabolite labeling from &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;C-glucose to compare WT and &lt;i&gt;Ndp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;\n                        &lt;i&gt;KO&lt;/i&gt;\n                    &lt;/sup&gt; retinas. In &lt;i&gt;Ndp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;\n                        &lt;i&gt;KO&lt;/i&gt;\n                    &lt;/sup&gt; retinas, we observe gene expression responses consistent with hypoxia in Muller glia and retinal neurons, and we find a metabolic shift that combines reduced flux through the TCA cycle with increased synthesis of serine, glycine, and glutathione. We also used single-cell RNA sequencing to compare the responses of individual cell types in &lt;i&gt;Ndp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;\n                        &lt;i&gt;KO&lt;/i&gt;\n                    &lt;/sup&gt; retinas with those in the hypoxic cerebral cortex of mice that were housed for 1 week in a reduced oxygen environment (7.5% oxygen). In the hypoxic cerebral cortex, glial transcriptome responses most closely resemble the response of Muller glia in the &lt;i&gt;Ndp&lt;/i&gt;&lt;sup&gt;\n                        &lt;i&gt;KO&lt;/i&gt;\n                    &lt;/sup&gt; retina. In both retina and brain, vascular endothelial cells activate a previously dormant tip cell gene expression program, which likely underlies the adaptive neoangiogenic response to chronic hypoxia. These analyses of retina and brain transcriptomes at single-cell resolution reveal both shared and cell type-specific changes in gene expression in response to chronic hypoxia, implying both shared and distinct cell type-specific physiologic responses. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>