<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">182</field>
<field name="content">A comparison of the contrast sensitivity function between age-matched phakic emmetropes and pseudophakic individuals with aspheric intraocular lenses.,&quot;Cold hypersensitivity in the hands and feet (CHHF) is frequent in Asian countries including Korea. The quality of life can be degraded by the symptoms of CHHF. In particular, gynecological disorders such as menstrual pain, infertility, leucorrhea, and irregular bleeding may be related to CHHF. Sipjeondaebo-tang (SDT) is widely used in the treatment of various diseases including CHHF by balancing Yin and Yang, restoring the deterioration of physiological function, and improving immunity. However, the efficacy of SDT in the treatment of CHHF has not been assessed in clinical trials. Therefore, we aimed to investigate the feasibility of a full randomized clinical trial of SDT for the treatment of CHHF in Korean women through this trial. This study will be a pilot, randomized, double-blind, two-arm, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter clinical trial. Women aged 19-59years who present with CHHF will be recruited from five university hospitals. A total of 60 subjects will be randomly assigned to a treatment group (SDT) or a placebo group at a 1:1 ratio. The subjects will receive 3g of either SDT or placebo three times daily for 8weeks. The primary outcome measures will be the Visual Analogue Scale scores of CHHF. The secondary outcome measures will be changes in body temperature in both the hands and the feet as measured using a thermometer and the Korean version of the World Health Organization Quality of Life Scale Abbreviated Version. This will be the first trial to investigate the efficacy and safety of SDT in the treatment of CHHF. This study will provide basic clinical information regarding Korean herbal medicine treatment of CHHF and a clinical basis for designing a full randomized clinical trial. ClinicalTrials.gov, NCT03374345 . Registered on 15 February 2018. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>