<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">187</field>
<field name="content">Sulfur Hexafluoride (SF&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;) versus Perfluoropropane (C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;) in the Intraoperative Management of Macular Holes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.,&quot;To report surgical outcomes of combined vitrectomy for vitreous floaters and phacoemulsification surgery with multifocal intraocular lens implantation. Retrospective, interventional, noncomparative case series of five eyes from five patients who underwent same-day combined phacoemulsification surgeries with apodized, diffractive multifocal intraocular lens implantation for cataract and pars plana vitrectomy for symptomatic vitreous opacities, that is, floaters. Primary outcomes were distance and near visual acuities, and resolution of symptoms. Secondary outcomes included intraocular pressure, refractive outcomes, and surgical complications. Mean logarithm of the minimum angle of resolution glare distance visual acuity improved from 0.36 (best-corrected Snellen 20/47) preoperatively to an uncorrected distance visual acuity of 0.05 (Snellen 20/23) at 6 months postoperatively (P = 0.042). All but one patient achieved multifocality with a near visual acuity of J2 or better. All patients noted subjective improvement in symptoms from floaters postoperatively. Mean intraocular pressure remained stable during follow-up. Two eyes ultimately required YAG capsulotomies for symptomatic posterior capsular opacification, one of which additionally received LASEK for refractive correction. Multifocality and improvement in symptoms from symptomatic vitreous opacities were observed in this pilot series of carefully selected patients who underwent combined phacovitrectomy with multifocal intraocular lens implantation. A high rate of retinal tears was found in these patients. Appropriate caution should be taken in preoperative assessment and patient selection for the combined procedure. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>