<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">191</field>
<field name="content">Optical Coherence Tomography Angiography Compared with Indocyanine Green Angiography in Central Serous Chorioretinopathy.,&quot;Attempted eye salvage for unilateral (cT2b/Group D) retinoblastoma may increase risk of tumor spread compared to primary enucleation. Identification of clinical features predictive of low histopathologic risk would support safe trial salvage. Retrospective, non-comparative single-institutional observational case series PARTICIPANTS: Children with unilateral cT2b/Group D retinoblastoma (January 2008-February 2018) managed with primary enucleation at the Hospital for Sick Children (SickKids), Toronto, Canada. Data included clinical features (intraocular pressure (IOP), optic nerve obscuration, macular involvement, tumor seeding and serous retinal detachment (RD) &gt;1 quadrant), timing to enucleation, histopathological findings and follow-up (metastasis and death). Primary outcome was low-risk (LR) (pT1/pT2) versus high-risk (HR) (pT3/pT4) (8th Edition American Joint Committee on Cancer) histopathology with Clinicopathologic correlations. Secondary outcomes were positive predictive values (probability that certain clinical features would predict LR histopathology) and negative predictive values (probability that absence of these clinical features would predict HR histopathology). Thirty-eight eyes were eligible with mean age of 21 months (range: 2-48) at diagnosis. All had vitreous seeding and normal IOP. The median diagnosis to enucleation interval was 4 days (range, 0-14) without parental refusals. Histopathology diagnosed 4/38-10.5% HR and 34/38-89.5% LR eyes. HR eyes demonstrated massive choroidal invasion (4/38-10.5%), or trans-scleral, extraocular and post-laminar optic nerve invasion (1/38-2.6%). Clinical findings included macular involvement (31/38-82%), complete optic nerve obscuration (27/38-74%), and RD (28/38-74%). The proportion of eyes with HR histopathology was 13% (4/31; 95%CI: 1- 25%) with macular involvement, 15% (4/27; 95%CI: 1-28%) with complete optic nerve obscuration, and 14% (4/28; 95%CI: 1- 27%) with RD. The predictability of LR histopathology was 100% (7/7; 95%CI: 47-100%) with macular sparing, 100% (10/10; 95%CI: 63-100%) with optic nerve visibility and 100% (10/10; 95%CI: 63-100%) with &lt;1 quadrant of RD. One child lacking all three clinical LR predictive features had HR histopathology (pT3a) developed metastases and died; other children are alive and well (mean follow-up 65 months). Presence of macular sparing, optic-nerve visibility and/or &lt;1 quadrant of RD predicted LR histopathology at primary enucleation, suggesting safe trial salvage. No clinical sign predicted HR histopathology. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>