<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">202</field>
<field name="content">FUNDUS AUTOFLUORESCENCE PREDICTING GROWTH OF A CHOROIDAL OSTEOMA IN A 13-YEAR-OLD GIRL.,&quot;Stargardt disease is the most common inherited juvenile macular dystrophy and is characterized by yellowish flecks across the posterior pole. The purpose of this study was to investigate fluorescence lifetime changes of retinal flecks over time using fluorescence lifetime imaging ophthalmoscopy. Longitudinal fluorescence lifetime data of 12 patients with Stargardt disease (mean age  SEM, 42.25  2.1 years; range, 28-58 years) were acquired using a fluorescence lifetime imaging ophthalmoscope based on a Heidelberg Engineering Spectralis system. Retinal autofluorescence was excited with a 470-nm laser. The emitted fluorescence was detected in two wavelength channels: a short spectral channel (498-560 nm) and a long spectral channel (560-720 nm). The mean retinal autofluorescence lifetimes were calculated and further analyzed with corresponding color fundus images, autofluorescence intensity images, and spectral domain optical coherence tomography. Patients were classified into three subtypes. All patients with Stargardt disease displayed characteristic autofluorescence lifetime patterns. Mean fluorescence lifetime values within areas of yellow flecks were significantly prolonged (long spectral channel 484 ps) compared with the surrounding tissue (long spectral channel 297 ps). In 91.6% of the eyes, flecks with short fluorescence lifetimes (long spectral channel 255 ps) were identified. Short lifetime flecks progressed to flecks with characteristic long lifetimes in 75.1% of eyes within a mean interval of 29.2 months (range 3-45 months). Between baseline and follow-up, the rate of newly developed short lifetime flecks (number/per year) based on subtypes was 2.62 in Group 1, 1.43 in Group 2, and 0.81 in Group 3. Recent onset flecks in Stargardt disease display short fluorescence lifetimes and convert into longer fluorescence lifetime flecks over time. This transition may represent a change in the composition of retinal deposits with accumulation of lipofuscin and retinoid by-products from the visual cycle. With emerging treatment options, these findings may prove useful to monitor disease progression and therapeutic effects.This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0 (CCBY), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>