<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">236</field>
<field name="content">Investigating the Immediate and Cumulative Effects of Isometric Squat Exercise for Different Weight Loads on Intraocular Pressure: A Pilot Study.,&quot;&lt;b&gt;Objective:&lt;/b&gt; To investigate the treatment of retinopathy of incontinentia pigmenti by anti-vascular endothelial growth factor. &lt;b&gt;Methods:&lt;/b&gt; Retrospective study of 5 patients(8 eyes) diagnosed retinopathy of incontinentia pigmenti from 2005 to 2017, including 0 males and 5 females (8 eyes involved) with an average age of 2.4 months(range, 1-5 months). Medical history and family history were recorded in detail for all children. We did the examination of anterior segment of the eyeball, vitreous body,fundus and intraocular pressure for the 5 patients(8eyes).What&apos;s more,wo also took pictures for fundus with the machine of Retcam. Fundus fluorescence angiography (FFA) was performed in 2 patients(4 eyes). Different surgical methods were selected according to the specific conditions of the eye and postoperative were observed. &lt;b&gt;Results:&lt;/b&gt; At the time of initial diagnosis, preretinal hemorrhage did not affect the macular region in 3 cases (5 eyes), pre retinal hemorrhage affected the macular region in 1 case(1 eye), the retinal neovascularization in 3 cases(5 eyes), the retinal detachment in 2 cases(2 eyes), and nonvascular zone of peripheral retinal in 5cases(8 eyes). Treatment and drug selection: 3 cases(5 eyes) were treated with injection anti-VEGF drug into vitreous body cavity, 1 case(1 eye) was treated with injection anti-VEGF drug into vitreous body cavity plus laser photocoagulation, 1 case(1 eye) was treated with anti-VEGF drugs plus vitrectomy. 1 case(1 eye) was treated with anti-VEGF drugs plus retinal cryotherapy and sclera bucking. In patients of injection anti-VEGF drug into vitreous body cavity, 2 cases(3 eyes) were given a single dose and 1 case (2 eyes) was given a repeated dose. Drug selection: 4 cases(6 eyes) ranibizumab injection (injection dose 0.025 ml), 1 case (2 eyes)conbercept injection (injection dose 0.025 ml). To follow-up date, etina was flat in 4 patients (7 eyes), epiretinal membrane in 2 patients(2 eyes), retinal detachment in 1 patient(1 eye). &lt;b&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/b&gt; The efficacy of anti-vascular endothelial growth factor in the treatment of retinopathy of incontinentia pigmenti was prelininarily confimed.However,the optimal use timing,dosage,local and systemic safety issues were needed to be further studied. &lt;i&gt;(Chin J Ophthalmol, 2019, 55:294-301)&lt;/i&gt;. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>