<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">239</field>
<field name="content">The effectiveness and safety of moxibustion for dry eye: Protocol for a systematic review.,&quot;&lt;b&gt;Objective:&lt;/b&gt; To investigate the ocular manifestations of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and syphilis coinfection. &lt;b&gt;Methods:&lt;/b&gt; A retrospective analysis of the ocular manifestations was carried out in 27 patients (54 eyes) diagnosed as syphilis and HIV coinfection by the Department of Infectious Medicine in Peking Union Medical College Hospital during the years of 2006-2017. The research included 26 males and 1 female, aging from 24 to 76 years old, with a mean age of 40.4012.94 years old. Ocular anterior segments were examined with slit-lamp microscope. Fundus examinations were conducted with papillary dilation, fundus photography. &lt;b&gt;Results:&lt;/b&gt; At the first visit, there were 2 eyes without light perception, 4 eyes with light perception, 1 eye with hand movement, 1 eye with finger counting, 2 eyes with 0.01-0.09 eyesight, 8 eyes with 0.1-0.2 eyesight, 12 eyes with 0.25-0.4 eyesight, 15 eyes with 0.5-0.9 eyesight, 9 eyes with 1.0-1.5 eyesight. Among the 27 patients (54 eyes) coinfected with HIV and syphilis, keratic precipitates were identified in 20 eyes, aqueous flare positive in 20 eyes, float positive in 15 eyes, and iris posterior synechias in 7 eyes. Nineteen eyes were diagnosed as syphilis uveitis, including 2 eyes with syphilis anterior uveitis and 17 eyes with syphilis panuveitis, among which, vitreous inflammatory opacity was observed in all 19 eyes, disk atrophy in 2 eyes, optic edema in 1 eye, vitreous hemorrhage in 1 eye, retinal detachment in 2 eyes, retinal hemorrhage and white vein in 1 eye. In addition, 8 eyes were diagnosed as HIV retinopathy, all manifested as cotton-wool spot. Among the 8 eyes, 4 were diagnosed as cytomegalovirus retinitis, 3 showed retinal yellow-white lesions, and 1 was in late phase which showed retinal pigmentation. The incidence of both HIV and syphilis coinfection patients and male homosexuality population increased. The most common ocular manifestation of HIV and syphilis coinfection was syphilis panuveitis. Six patients first visited the Department of Ophthalmology, and were then diagnosed as HIV and syphilis coinfection. &lt;b&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/b&gt; The ocular manifestations of HIV and syphilis coinfection are diversified, which can be manifested as fundus necrotic lesions as well as anterior and posterior inflammatory. For HIV positive patients, syphilis serologic test should be routinely performed. The same, syphilis positive patients should be tested for HIV serum antibodies, in order to improve the diagnosis level of HIV/syphilis coinfection and give timely etiological treatment, which is of vital importance for saving visual acuity. &lt;i&gt;(Chin J Ophthalmol, 2019, 55:267-272)&lt;/i&gt;. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>