<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">246</field>
<field name="content">Long-Term Descemetocele Management With Prosthetic Replacement of the Ocular Surface Ecosystem (PROSE) Treatment.,&quot;To evaluate geographic variation and characterize the relative contributions of patient characteristics, physician practice, and geographic region on variation in primary rhegmatogenous retinal detachment (RRD) management. Retrospective claims-based analysis PARTICIPANTS: 12,779 commercially-insured patients with incident RRD diagnosed between 2008 and 2016. We determined whether patients underwent primary RRD repair within 60 days of diagnosis, and identified type of repair performed. We identified physician ID for diagnosis and treatment, and characterized geography by Combined Statistical Areas (CSA) or Core-Based Statistical Area (CBSA). We used multilevel mixed effects logistic regression models to characterize patient-, physician-, and geographic-level variation in whether patients underwent RRD repair, and multilevel mixed effects multinomial models to characterize variation in repair type. For each model, we evaluated patient fixed effects and physician random effects nested within geographic random effects. We estimated intra-class correlation coefficients and variance partition coefficients, respectively, to compare relative contributions of patient, physician, and geography to overall variation. Odds ratios for RRD repair, variation estimates for patient, physician, and geography. The majority of incident RRD patients received treatment within 60 days of diagnosis. Pars plana vitrectomy was most common (49%), followed by laser barricade (23%), scleral buckle and pneumatic retinopexy (both 11%), and cryotherapy (5%). Physician-level variation had greater impact on receipt of any treatment than geographic-level variation (estimated variance coefficients of 1.09 and 0.32, respectively). Patient-level characteristics were estimated to represent approximately 82% of overall variation in receipt of any repair, versus 16% from physician-level and 2% from geographic-level factors. Among RRD patients who underwent repair, estimated variance coefficients were 0.07 for geography and 3.37 for physician. Physician-level factors represented approximately 50% of total variation in repair type, followed by patient-level (49%), and geographic-level factors (1%). RRD repair decisions are influenced by patient-level and physician-level factors, less so by geographic variation. Patient characteristics account for most of the variation in receipt of repair, and physician practice accounts for most of the variation in choice of procedure. These findings indicate a need for additional studies to understand drivers behind differences in care and clinical outcomes and to identify barriers in access to care. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>