<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">247</field>
<field name="content">Repeatability and Agreement of a Swept-Source Optical Coherence Tomography-Based Biometer IOLMaster 700 Versus a Scheimpflug Imaging-Based Biometer AL-Scan in Cataract Patients.,&quot;and Objective: Epidemic and seasonal infectious conjunctivitis outbreaks can adversely impact education, workforce and economy. Yet conjunctivitis is typically not a reportable disease, potentially delaying mitigating intervention. Our study objective was to determine if conjunctivitis epidemics could be identified using Google Trends search data. Search data for conjunctivitis-related and control search terms from 5 years and countries worldwide were obtained. Country and term were masked. Temporal scan statistics were applied to identify candidate epidemics. Candidates were then assessed for geotemporal concordance with an a priori defined collection of known reported conjunctivitis outbreaks, as a measure of sensitivity. Populations by country that searched Google&apos;s search engine using our study terms. Percent of known conjunctivitis outbreaks also found in the same country and time period by our candidate epidemics, identified from conjunctivitis-related searches RESULTS: We identified 135 candidate conjunctivitis epidemic periods from 77 countries. Compared to our a priori defined collection of known reported outbreaks, candidate conjunctivitis epidemics identified 18 out of 26 (69% sensitivity) of the reported country-wide and/or island nation-wide outbreaks, 9 out of 20 (45% sensitivity) of the reported region and/or district-wide outbreaks, but far fewer nosocomial and reported smaller outbreaks. Similar overall and individual sensitivity, as well as specificity, was found on a country-level basis. We also found that 83% of our candidate epidemics had start dates prior (of those, 20% were over 12 weeks prior) to their concurrent reported outbreak&apos;s report issuance date. Permutation tests provided evidence that on average conjunctivitis candidate epidemics occurred geotemporally closer to outbreak reports than chance alone would suggest (P &lt;0.001), unlike control term candidates (P=0.40). Conjunctivitis outbreaks can be detected using temporal scan analysis of Google search data alone, with over 80% detected prior to an outbreak report&apos;s issuance date, some as early as the reported outbreak&apos;s start date. Future approaches using data from smaller regions, social media and more search terms may further improve sensitivity and cross-validate detected candidates, allowing identification of candidate conjunctivitis epidemics from Internet search data to potentially complementarily benefit traditional reporting and detection systems to improve epidemic awareness. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>