<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">254</field>
<field name="content">Inter-visit measurement variability of conjunctival vasculature and circulation in habitual contact lens wearers and non-lens wearers.,&quot;Dysfunction and eventual loss of retinal pigment epithelial (RPE) cells is a hallmark of atrophic age-related macular degeneration (AMD), and linked to oxidative and nitrosative damage. Herein, we use high-throughput screening (HTS) to identify compounds that protect human RPE cells from oxidative stress-induced cell death and elucidate the possible mechanism of action. HTS was used to identify compounds that protect RPE cells from oxidative damage. We then tested the identified compound(s) in models of RPE stress, including tert-butyl hydroperoxide (TBHP) exposure, UV-B-mediated light damage and nitrosative stress to the basement membrane using ARPE-19cells, primary human RPE and induced-pluripotent stem cell (iPSC)-derived RPE cells from patients with AMD. Quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR) was used to detect gene expression of oxidative stress- and apoptosis-related genes and mitochondrial function was measured by the Seahorse XF96 analyzer to elucidate possible mechanisms of action. Five thousand and sixty-five compounds were screened, and of these, 12 compounds were active based on their ability to improve cell viability after exposure to TBHP. After chemical structure review, we identified ciclopirox olamine as a potent inhibitor of oxidative damage to RPE cells. Ciclopirox olamine increased cell viability in ARPE-19cells treated with TBHP, UV-B light or on nitrite-treated ECM by 1.68-fold, 1.54-fold and 4.3-fold, respectively (p&lt;0.01). Treatment with TBHP altered expression of genes related to oxidative stress and apoptosis, which was reversed by pretreatment with ciclopirox olamine. Ciclopirox olamine improved mitochondrial function in TBHP-exposed ARPE-19cells and iPSC-derived RPE cells. Ciclopirox olamine protected primary human RPE cells and iPSC-derived RPE cells from the oxidative stress or damaged basement membrane. HTS of bioactive FDA-approved libraries and follow-up studies can be used to identify small molecules (including ciclopirox olamine) that protect RPE cells exposed to various stressors associated with disease progression of AMD. This strategy can be used to identify potential compounds for treatment and prevention of AMD. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>