<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">300</field>
<field name="content">[Do children with strabismus receive ophthalmic treatment? : Results from the KiGGS (German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Children and Adolescents) baseline survey (2003-2006)].,&quot;Adipose-derived stem cells (ASCs) are multipotent mesenchymal progenitor cells that have functional and phenotypic overlap with pericytes lining microvessels in adipose tissue. The role of CD140b [platelet-derived growth factor receptor-  (PDGFR-)], a constitutive marker expressed by ASCs, in the angiogenic behavior of human retinal endothelial cells (HREs) is not known. CD140b was knocked down in ASCs using targeted siRNA and lipofectamine transfection protocol. Both CD140b+ and CD140b- ASCs were tested for their proliferation (WST-1 reagent), adhesion (laminin-1 coated plates), and migration (wound-scratch assay). Angiogenic effect of CD140b+ and CD140b- ASCs on HREs was examined by co-culturing ASCs:HREs in 12:1 ratio for 6 days followed by visualization of vascular network by Isolectin B4 staining. The RayBio Membrane-Based Antibody Array was used to assess differences in human cytokines released by CD140b+ or CD140b- ASCs. Knockdown of CD140b in ASCs resulted in a significant 50% decrease in proliferation rate, 25% decrease in adhesion ability to Laminin-1, and 50% decrease in migration rate, as compared to CD140b+ ASCs. Direct contact of ASCs expressing CD140b+ with HREs resulted in robust vascular network formation that was significantly reduced with using CD140b- ASCs. Of the 80 proteins tested, 45 proteins remained unchanged (&gt;0.5-&lt;1.5 fold), 6 proteins including IL-10 downregulated (&lt;0.5 fold) and 29 proteins including IL-16 &amp; TNF- were upregulated (&gt;1.5 fold) in CD140b- ASCs compared to CD140b+ ASCs. Our data demonstrate a substantial role for CD140b in the intrinsic abilities of ASCs and their angiogenic influence on HREs. Future studies are needed to fully explore the signaling of CD140b in ASCs &lt;i&gt;in vivo&lt;/i&gt; for retinal regeneration. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>