<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">320</field>
<field name="content">Patient-Sharing Relations in the Treatment of Diabetes and Their Implications for Health Information Exchange: Claims-Based Analysis.,&quot;To develop a methodology to correlate optical coherence tomography (OCT) images and histopathological sections from the same eye. Part 1: To determine the best fixative for optimal OCT and histopathological analysis in post-mortem eyes. Part 2: A protocol is proposed to correlate histopathological features and OCT scans from the same post-mortem eyes. Experimental study. Part 1: Twenty-three rabbit eyes and 14 post-mortem human eyes. Part 2: Nineteen post-mortem human eyes. Part 1: Six different fixatives were tested, and specimens were evaluated on 4 criteria: globe shape, structure opacification, retinal detachment, and nuclear details. Part 2: Based on the findings from Part 1, fixed human eyes were imaged using OCT. Orientation-controlled histopathological processing was performed to obtain serial tissue sections from paraffin embedded tissue, which were matched to corresponding OCT images. Part 1: Of the 6 fixatives, 2% glutaraldehyde and Davidson&apos;s solution met the proposed criteria in rabbit eyes. Of these, glutaraldehyde showed similar results in human eyes and was selected for Part 2. Part 2: Using anatomical landmarks, cross-sectional histopathological sections in the same orientation as the OCT images were correlated to their corresponding OCT images. Retinal lesions such as a macular hole, an epiretinal membrane, and the presence of drusen were easily correlated, proving the reliability of our methodology. Moreover, the photoreceptor&apos;s inner/outer junction was correlated to a hyperreflective band on OCT. A standardized protocol was developed to correlate OCT images and histopathological findings by generating serial cross-sections of the retina, which can be used to better understand otherwise ambiguous OCT findings. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>