<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">330</field>
<field name="content">Effect of High Myopia on Optic Nerve Head by Confocal Scanning Laser Ophthalmoscopy in Nepalese Eyes.,&quot;To identify factors associated with secondary surgical intervention after glaucoma filtration surgery. Population-based retrospective cohort. Patient records with billing claims for a primary glaucoma filtration surgery occurring between April 2003 and March 2015 were identified. Each identified record was examined for instances of secondary glaucoma surgeries within the patient&apos;s first postoperative year. Baseline characteristics of patients who required secondary surgical intervention were compared with those who did not. A multivariable Cox proportional hazards model was used to calculate hazard ratios. Within a cohort of 10,097 patients, 349 (3.46%) underwent a secondary surgical intervention within the first postoperative year. Interventions were less frequent after surgeries that included an indwelling drainage device (HR=0.58 95% CI, 0.37-0.89), phacoemulsification (HR=0.33, 0.21-0.52), or both (HR=0.09, 0.03-0.31). Patients with preoperative aminoglycoside and mydriatic exposure had significantly increased risk of secondary surgical intervention (HR=3.19, 1.89-5.36) and (HR=2.32, 1.49-3.61). Patients who underwent surgery on their contralateral eye experienced secondary surgical interventions more frequently: 7.44 per 10,000 person-days (versus 1.18 per 10,000 person-days, p &lt; 0.0001). No significant differences in the rates of secondary surgical intervention were observed for patients taking different classes of glaucoma medications or those exposed to higher amounts of benzalkonium chloride. In Ontario, the overall rates of secondary surgical interventions in the first postoperative year are low but significantly higher in certain patient populations. Further work is required to address the higher rate of secondary surgical intervention in patients with a history of certain perioperative eye drop medications and those who require sequential-bilateral procedures. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>