<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">336</field>
<field name="content">Comparison of Blue and Green Confocal Scanning Laser Ophthalmoscope Imaging to Detect Retinal Nerve Fiber Layer Defects.,&quot;Several Canadian health authorities have defunded preoperative cataract history and physical examinations performed by general practitioners. While these authorities suggest that such decisions are evidence-based, we are unaware of reviews addressing this topic, nor have health authorities been forthcoming with evidence used in their decision-making processes. The objective of this study is to perform a comprehensive review of the literature regarding the value of preoperative histories and physical examinations in cataract surgery. Systematic review. The following databases were searched: PubMed, MEDLINE, Cochrane Library, Google Scholar, Web of Science, EMBASE, CINAHL, and BIOSIS Previews. Only higher-level forms of evidence were assessed, including randomized controlled trials, cohort, and case-control studies. Two reviewers independently assessed titles and abstracts for concordance with inclusion criteria. Disagreements between authors were resolved by discussion. We identified 3 articles that met our inclusion criteria: two prospective and one retrospective cohort studies. These articles suggest traditional preoperative histories and physical examinations could be replaced by a health questionnaire (Jastrzebski et al. and Reeves et al.) or eliminated altogether (Alboim et al.). Scientific literature presently contains 3 studies suggesting that preoperative histories and physical examinations could be modified or eliminated. However, methodological weaknesses and data analysis derived from these studies suggests defunding preoperative medical examination may be premature. While finding efficiencies in medical care is admirable, physicians should be cautious in accepting recommendations that reduce checks ensuring perioperative safety. Further studies of better methodological quality should be completed to clarify the present evidence. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>