<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">344</field>
<field name="content">Multimodal imaging including optical coherence tomography angiography in patients with type B Niemann-Pick disease.,&quot;The aim of this study was to evaluate thiol/disulfide homeostasis and ischemia-modified albumin levels with primary open-angle glaucoma, ocular hypertension, and control group; also to interpret the correlation between these biochemical parameters and retinal nerve fiber layer analysis. In a prospective cross-sectional study, 30 primary open-angle glaucoma cases, 30 ocular hypertension cases, and 30 control subjects were included in the study. Native thiol, total thiol, and disulfide measurements and disulfide/native thiol, disulfide/total thiol, and native thiol/total thiol ratios were evaluated as thiol-disulfide homeostasis. Albumin and ischemia-modified albumin parameters were also evaluated. All cases underwent detailed ophthalmologic examination including visual acuity, retinal nerve fiber layer via optical coherence tomography, intraocular pressure, and central corneal thickness measurements and visual field analysis by 24-2 Swedish Interactive Threshold Algorithm (SITA) Standard visual field test. Primary open-angle glaucoma group had significantly higher ischemia-modified albumin values than ocular hypertension and control group (p&lt;0.001). Native thiol and total thiol values of control group were statistically higher than those of primary open-angle glaucoma and ocular hypertension groups. The correlation between the temporal retinal nerve fiber layer value and ischemia-modified albumin, disulfide/native thiol, and disulfide/total thiol values of the primary open-angle glaucoma patients included in the study was moderate correlation in negative direction (r=-0.46, r=-0.39, r=-0.39, respectively), whereas there was a statistically significant moderate correlation in positive direction between the native thiol/total thiol values (r=0.39) (p&lt;0.05). These findings have reinforced the role of oxidative stress in the etiopathogenesis of primary open-angle glaucoma, suggesting that the thinning retinal nerve fiber layer may be associated with oxidative stress in favor of prooxidant shift. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>