<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">345</field>
<field name="content">Mechanisms of neurodegeneration in a preclinical autosomal dominant retinitis pigmentosa knock-in model with a Rho&lt;sup&gt;D190N&lt;/sup&gt; mutation.,&quot;To investigate the potential correlation between complement factor B polymorphisms and age-related macular degeneration. We retrieved relevant articles systematically by searching PubMed and Web of Science databases. The pooled odds ratios and 95% confidence intervals were calculated for five complement factor B polymorphism rs641153, rs4151667, rs1048709, rs2072633, and rs12614 using data from included articles in both random effects and fixed effect models. Subgroup meta-analysis based on age-related macular degeneration type, choroidal neovascular disease (rs641153 and rs4151667), geographic atrophy (rs641153 and rs4151667), and races was also performed. In the overall comparison, we observed that the distribution of rs641153 and the risk of age-related macular degeneration were significantly correlated (p&lt;0.00001). Similar results were obtained in subgroup analysis based on race (Caucasians, p&lt;0.00001; Asians, p=0.003) and age-related macular degeneration type (choroidal neovascular disease, p&lt;0.00001; geographic atrophy, p=0.04). As for complement factor B rs4151667, the genotypic effects were also demonstrated statistically significant in overall analysis (p&lt;0.00001) and only in Caucasians diagnosed with choroidal neovascular disease (p=0.004), but not in Asians. Moreover, no statistically significant correlations between the complement factor B polymorphisms rs1048709 (p=0.63), rs2072633 (p=0.72), rs12614 (p=0.98) and susceptibility to age-related macular degeneration were detected in either overall or subgroup analysis. Collectively, we demonstrated that the complement factor B genes rs641153 and rs4151667, but not rs1048709, rs2072633, rs12614, were associated with the susceptibility of age-related macular degeneration and might play predictive roles in future age-related macular degeneration diagnosis. More studies are needed to verify these findings. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>