<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">346</field>
<field name="content">Spontaneous resolution of myopic retinoschisis.,&quot;Primary objective was to assess associations between annual surgeon case volume and visual acuity outcomes following cataract surgery. Secondary objectives included (i) assessing for associations between other case and patient characteristics and post-operative visual acuity outcomes and (ii) assessing for associations between annual surgeon case volume and complication rates. Database study. All adult eyes that underwent small-incision or phacoemulsification cataract surgery with intraocular lens placement at the Aravind Eye Hospital in Madurai, India during calendar year 2015. Descriptive statistics were used to characterize the study population. Uncorrected visual acuity (UCVA) at follow-up was assessed relative to annual surgeon case volume and other case/demographic factors using bivariate linear regression with random effects modeling. Factors with p-value &lt; 0.20 on bivariate regression were included in multivariate linear regression with random effects modeling. Post-operative UCVA following cataract surgery. Of a total of 91,084 surgeries, 35,880 eyes were included in this study. Cases were performed by 69 surgeons, who varied in annual case volume from 76 to 2900 cases during the study period. Increasing annual surgeon case volume was independently associated with a statistically significant but clinically modest improvement in UCVA in phacoemulsification cataract extraction (PECE) but not in small-incision cataract surgery (SICS). This association was most pronounced when comparing surgeons with case volumes of 350 PECE/year or fewer; surgeons with greater volume than this had results largely similar to one another. Similarly, increased annual case volume was associated with significantly lower complication rates, both in PECE and SICS. Lower patient age was independently associated with improved visual acuity outcomes and lower complication rates in both PECE and SICS. Greater surgeon experience was associated with lower complication rates in PECE but not SICS, and there was no significant association with visual acuity outcomes. High-volume cataract surgeons had improved visual acuity outcomes in PECE and lower complication rates in PECE and SICS. These findings further support the benefit of high-output ophthalmology clinics wherein individual surgeons can perform a high number of cataract extractions annually, particularly in developing nations where there is a large backlog of untreated cataract and the cataract-to-surgeon ratio is high. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>