<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">361</field>
<field name="content">&quot;The secreted Ly6/uPAR-related protein-1 suppresses neutrophil binding, chemotaxis, and transmigration through human umbilical vein endothelial cells.&quot;,&quot;Incomplete tear film spreading and eyelid closure can cause defective renewal of the ocular surface and air exposure-induced epithelial keratopathy (EK). In this study, we characterized the role of autophagy in mediating the ocular surface changes leading to EK. Human corneal epithelial cells (HCECs) and C57BL/6 mice were employed as EK models, respectively. Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) evaluated changes in HCECs after air exposure. Each of these models was treated with either an autophagy inhibitor [chloroquine (CQ) or 3-methyladenine (3-MA)] or activator [Rapamycin (Rapa)]. Immunohistochemistry assessed autophagy-related proteins, LC3 and p62 expression levels. Western blotting confirmed the expression levels of the autophagy-related proteins [Beclin1 and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR)], the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress-related proteins (PERK, eIF2 and CHOP) and the PI3K/Akt/mTOR signalling pathway-related proteins. Real-time quantitative PCR (qRT-PCR) determined IL-1, IL-6 and MMP9 gene expression levels. The TUNEL assay detected apoptotic cells. TEM identified autophagic vacuoles in both EK models. Increased LC3 puncta formation and decreased p62 immunofluorescent staining and Western blotting confirmed autophagy induction. CQ treatment increased TUNEL positive staining in HCECs, while Rapa had an opposite effect. Similarly, CQ injection enhanced air exposure-induced apoptosis and inflammation in the mouse corneal epithelium, which was inhibited by Rapa treatment. Furthermore, the phosphorylation status of PERK and eIF2 and CHOP expression increased in both EK models indicating that ER stress-induced autophagy promoted cell survival. Taken together, air exposure-induced autophagy is indispensable for the maintenance of corneal epithelial physiology and cell survival. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>