<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">38</field>
<field name="content">Diagnosing and quantifying a common deficit in multiple sclerosis: Internuclear ophthalmoplegia.,&quot;&lt;b&gt;Background:&lt;/b&gt; The assessment of specific polysaccharide antibody production plays a pivotal role in the diagnosis of humoral primary immunodeficiencies (PID). The response to 23-valent pneumococcal vaccine (PPV) remains the gold standard for the diagnosis of polysaccharide antibodies. However, in Spain, the interpretation of pure polysaccharide 23-valent immunization is hampered by the high endemicity of pneumococcal disease and the generalization of the 13-valent adjuvant pneumococcal vaccination. Specific Typhim Vi vaccination (TV) immunoglobulin G IgG response to immunization is useful in adult PID, but there is no data regarding children. &lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt; To evaluate the clinical utility of TV IgG production as a diagnostic tool to determine anti-polysaccharide antibody production deficiency in children, when the response to PPV is unclear and isolated determination of serotypes is unfeasible. &lt;b&gt;Methods:&lt;/b&gt; We conducted a single-institution prospective observational study on 61 children with recurrent infections. Baseline specific antibodies against PPV and TV were evaluated. In 28 children (46%), the response to the production of antibodies confirmed a clinical suspicion of humoral PID, and they were therefore immunized with 23-valent pneumococcal vaccine and Typhim Vi. Both specific antibody responses were measured by ELISA (The Binding Site Group Ltd, Birmingham, UK) using previously published cut-offs. &lt;b&gt;Results:&lt;/b&gt; Seventy percent of the 61 children displayed baseline PPV IgG &gt; 27 mg/L, whereas only 8% showed TV IgG &gt; 28 U/mL (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.0001). Twenty-one of 28 children (75%) achieved a 3-fold increase in post-vaccination TV IgG levels, whereas only 3% achieved a 4-fold increase in PPV IgG post vaccination, mainly due to high baseline PPV IgG titers. When we classified children according to their response to TV as responders or non-responders and compared this with the well-known clinical warning signs of the Jeffrey Modell Foundation. The proportions of children with history of pneumonia and the need for intravenous antibiotics were significantly higher in TV IgG non-responders than in TV IgG responders (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.02 and &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.01, respectively). &lt;b&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/b&gt; Response to TV can be considered an ancillary diagnostic tool to determine polysaccharide antibodies in children, particularly when isolated determination of pneumococcal serotypes is not feasible. TV provides a useful asset for clinicians in the era of conjugate PPV vaccination, with clinical relevance. Further research is warranted for validation. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>