<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">381</field>
<field name="content">Optimizing optical coherence tomography and histopathology correlation in retinal imaging.,&quot;Background Evidence of the role of systolic blood pressure ( SBP ) in development of severe diabetic retinopathy is not strong, although the adverse effect of low diastolic blood pressure has been a partial explanation. We assessed the predictive ability of incident severe diabetic retinopathy between pulse pressure ( PP ) which considers both SBP and diastolic blood pressure, compared with SBP . Methods and Results Eligible patients (12242, 83% men) aged 19 to 72years from a nationwide claims database were analyzed for a median observational 4.8-year period. Severe diabetic retinopathy was defined as vision-threatening treatment-required diabetic eye diseases. Multivariate Cox regression analysis revealed that hazard ratios (95% CI ) of treatment-required diabetic eye diseases for 1 increment of standard deviation and the top tertile compared with the bottom tertile were 1.39 (1.21-1.60) and 1.72 (1.17-2.51), respectively, for PP and 1.22 (1.05-1.41) and 1.43 (0.97-2.11), respectively, for SBP adjusted for age, sex, body mass index, hemoglobin A1c, fasting plasma glucose, lipids, and smoking status. In a model with SBP and PP simultaneously as covariates, the hazard ratios of only PP (hazard ratios [95% CI ], 1.57 [1.26-1.96]) but not SBP (0.85 [0.68-1.07]) were statistically significant. Delong test revealed a significant difference in the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve between PP and SBP (area under the receiver operating characteristic curve [95% CI ], 0.58 [0.54-0.63] versus 0.54 [0.50-0.59]; P=0.03). The strongest predictor remained as hemoglobin A1c (area under the receiver operating characteristic curve [95% CI ], 0.80 [0.77-0.84]). Conclusions After excluding the significant impact of glycemic control, PP in comparison with SBP is a better predictor of severe diabetic retinopathy, suggesting a role of diastolic blood pressure and arterial stiffness in pathology. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>