<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">390</field>
<field name="content">Randomized crossover trial comparing effectiveness and tolerability of generic and brand-name travoprost.,&quot;To compare the intravitreal concentrations of cellular mediators involved in neurodegeneration, inflammation, and angiogenesis in patients with proliferative diabetic retinopathy and other vitreoretinal diseases. A multiplex bead immunoassay was used to measure vitreous levels of pigment epithelium-derived factor, serum amyloid P, C-reactive protein, complement C4, alpha-1 antitrypsin, vascular endothelial growth factor, platelet-derived growth factor-AA, platelet-derived growth factor-BB, interleukin-6, interleukin-8, interleukin-10, tumor necrosis factor alpha and beta in patients undergoing 23-gauge vitrectomy for proliferative diabetic retinopathy and other diagnoses (control group). We evaluated 55 patients, of whom 24 had proliferative diabetic retinopathy and 31 had other diagnoses including vitreous hemorrhage, retinal detachment, macular hole, and epiretinal membrane. Patients with proliferative diabetic retinopathy demonstrated increased levels of serum amyloid P (85.49 vs. 31.38 ng/mL); C-reactive protein (59.89 vs. 41.75 ng/mL), vascular endothelial growth factor (2,330.11 vs. 554.25 pg/mL; p&lt;0.001), platelet-derived growth factor A (127.32 vs. 39.11 pg/mL), platelet-derived growth factor B (29.37 vs. 7.12 pg/mL), interleukin-6 (69.37 vs. 33.58 pg/mL), interleukin-8 (175.25 vs. 59.71 pg/mL), and interleukin-10 (3.70 vs. 1.88 pg/mL); all p&lt;0.004 when compared with the control group. Levels of pigment epithelium-derived factor (30.06 vs. 27.48 ng/mL; p=0.295), complement C4 (570.78 vs. 366.24 ng/mL; p=0.069), and alpha-1-antitrypsin (359.27 vs. 522.44 ng/mL; p=0.264) were not significantly different between the groups. Intravitreal levels of tumor necrosis factor-alpha and tumor necrosis factor-beta were undetectable. Serum Amyloid P, C-reactive protein, platelet-derived growth factor A, platelet-derived growth factor B, interleukin-6, and interleukin-8 were correlated positively with vascular endothelial growth factor. Cellular mediators involved in neurodegeneration and inflammation demonstrated increased levels in the vitreous humor of patients with proliferative diabetic retinopathy and may be part of the pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>