<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">394</field>
<field name="content">Descemet membrane endothelial keratoplasty in iridocorneal endothelial syndrome and posterior polymorphous corneal dystrophy.,&quot;Though several procedures of IOL implantation have been described (sutured scleral fixation, intra-scleral fixation, angle-supported anterior chamber, and anterior chamber or retropupillary iris-claw IOLs), there are no randomized trials which are comparing different techniques. Hence, the surgical treatment of aphakia still remains controversial and challenging. The purpose of this study was to compare the long-term efficacy and the rate of complications of anterior versus posterior Iris-claw intraocular lenses (IOL) implantation to correct for the treatment of aphakia without sufficient capsule support. Consecutive eyes having secondary implantation of aphakic iris-fixated IOLs with a follow-up of at least 5 years were considered. Mean correct distance visual acuity (CDVA) changes, percentage of eyes with CDVA improvement, mean corneal endothelial cell density (CECD) loss and the rate of other complications were used for statistical analysis. The study evaluated a total of 180 eyes (Group A: 87 anterior chamber iris-claw fixation, Group B: 93 retropupillary iris-claw implantation) of 180 consecutive different patients, with aphakia of various reasons. CDVA improved significantly in both groups after surgery (P&lt;0.001, ANOVA), and was remarkably higher than baseline in both groups from first week and during the entire follow-up (P&lt;0.001, Tukey&apos;s Honest Significant Difference). There was no statistically significant difference in CDVA between the two groups during each follow-up visits (P = NS, unpaired t-test) and in the CDVA improvement percentage between the two groups (P = 0.882, Chi-square test). No significant changes in CECD were noted after surgery in both groups (ANOVA Group A: P = 0.067, Group B: P = 0.330P). No intra-operative complications occurred in both groups. There was no statistically significant difference in the rate of complications between the two groups (P = NS, Chi-square test), except for pigment precipitates which were higher in Group A (P&lt;0.05, Chi-square test). Five-year follow-up shows that secondary implantation of aphakic IOLs is effective and safe for the correction treatment of aphakia in eyes without capsule support. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>