<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">406</field>
<field name="content">Complement factor B gene polymorphisms and risk of age-related macular degeneration: A meta-analysis.,&quot;To investigate the predictive value of preoperative anterior chamber aqueous flare levels measured by laser flare photometry for surgical success of idiopathic macular holes in addition to preoperative anatomic characteristics. Records of 105 consecutive eyes with full-thickness idiopathic macular holes which underwent pars plana vitrectomy with internal limiting membrane peeling and sulfur hexafluoride 20% (SF&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;20%) endotamponade were reviewed retrospectively. All patients underwent preoperative measurements of anterior chamber aqueous flare and anatomical idiopathic macular hole characteristics evaluated by optical coherence tomography: macular hole inner opening diameter, macular hole minimum linear diameter, macular hole base diameter, and macular hole height. Best-corrected visual acuity results were recorded pre- and postoperatively. In 17 (16.2%) of 105 eyes primary closure of idiopathic macular hole failed, whereas in 88 eyes (83.8%) closure was achieved. Between both groups, preoperative macular hole minimum linear diameter (p=0.001) and macular hole inner opening diameter (p=0.006) were statistically different. Failure rates were significantly lower in eyes with macular hole minimum linear diameter&lt;400m (7.4% vs 32.4%; p=0.013) and preoperative macular hole minimum linear diameter showed moderate correlation with pre- and postoperative best-corrected visual acuity results (r=0.512; p&lt;0.001; r=0.612; p&lt;0.001). Mean anterior chamber aqueous flare of 11.59.9pc/ms in eyes with anatomical closure and 11.86.4pc/ms in unclosed cases was comparable (p=0.28) and did not correlate with anatomical or functional results. Eyes with idiopathic macular hole400m in size have a significantly higher failure rate following standardized pars plana vitrectomy with internal limiting membrane peeling and SF&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;20% endotamponade. Preoperative macular hole minimum linear diameter and macular hole inner opening diameter seem to be associated with surgical outcome in idiopathic macular hole, whereas anterior chamber aqueous flare level does not provide additional predictive value. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>