<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">427</field>
<field name="content">Glaucoma in the Age of E-learning.,&quot;To investigate the role of neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) and NET-associated proteins in the pathogenesis of oGVHD and whether dismantling of NETs with heparin reduces those changes. Ocular surface washings from oGVHD patients and healthy subjects were analyzed. Isolated peripheral blood human neutrophils were stimulated to generate NETs and heparinized NETs. We performed in vitro experiments using cell lines (corneal epithelial, conjunctival fibroblast, meibomian gland (MG) epithelial and T cells), and in vivo experiments using murine models, and compared the effects of NETs, heparinized NETs, NET-associated proteins and neutralizing antibodies to NET-associated proteins. Neutrophils, exfoliated epithelial cells, NETs and NET-associated proteins (extracellular DNA, Neutrophil Elastase, Myeloperoxidase, Oncostatin M (OSM), Neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin (NGAL) and LIGHT/TNFSF14) are present in ocular surface washings (OSW) and mucocellular aggregates (MCA). Eyes with high number of neutrophils in OSW have more severe signs and symptoms of oGVHD. NETs (and OSM) cause epitheliopathy in murine corneas. NETs (and LIGHT/TNFSF14) increase proliferation of T cells. NETs (and NGAL) inhibit proliferation and differentiation of MG epithelial cells. NETs enhance proliferation and myofibroblast transformation of conjunctival fibroblasts. Sub-anticoagulant dose Heparin (100 IU/mL) dismantles NETs and reduces epithelial, fibroblast, T cell and MG cell changes induced by NETs. NETs and NET-associated proteins contribute to the pathological changes of oGVHD (corneal epitheliopathy, conjunctival cicatrization, ocular surface inflammation and meibomian gland disease). Our data points to the potential of NET-associated proteins (OSM or LIGHT/TNFSF14) to serve as biomarkers and NET-dismantling biologics (heparin eye drops) as treatment for oGVHD. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>