<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">429</field>
<field name="content">Association of rs613872 and Trinucleotide Repeat Expansion in the TCF4 Gene of German Patients With Fuchs Endothelial Corneal Dystrophy.,&quot;Evaluate the safety and efficacy of OTX-101, a novel aqueous nanomicellar formulation of cyclosporine (0.09%), in the treatment of subjects with dry eye disease (DED). A randomized, multicenter, vehicle-controlled, double-masked, phase 3 clinical trial. Adults (18-90 years of age) with a history and clinical diagnosis of DED, a global symptom score 40 (0-100 range), and a lissamine green conjunctival staining score of 3 and 9 (0-12 range) in at least 1 eye. Eligible subjects entered a run-in period of 14-20 days, in which all subjects administered vehicle twice daily. Subjects that remained eligible at the baseline (day 0) visit were randomized in a 1:1 ratio to twice-daily treatment with OTX-101 0.09% or vehicle for 84 days. Efficacy assessments included signs (unanesthetized Schirmer tear test, corneal and conjunctival staining) and symptoms (global symptom score) of DED. The primary endpoint was the proportion of eyes with a clinically meaningful improvement (increase of 10 mm) in Schirmer test score at day 84. Safety evaluations included adverse events (AE), visual acuity, and intraocular pressure monitoring, as well as slit-lamp and dilated ophthalmoscopy/fundus examinations. A total of 744 subjects were randomized and received study medication (371 to OTX-101 0.09% and 373 to vehicle). The primary endpoint was achieved; a significantly greater percentage of eyes in the OTX-101 0.09% treatment group experienced an increase of  10 mm in the Schirmer test score at day 84 (OTX-101 0.09%: 16.6%; vehicle: 9.2%; P &lt; 0.001). Significant improvements relative to vehicle were also observed for corneal (days 28, 56, and 84) and conjunctival staining (days 56 and 84). The global symptom score was reduced from baseline in both treatment groups by approximately 30%; however, no significant separation between groups was observed. The OTX-101 0.09% formulation was well-tolerated. Treatment emergent AEs were primarily mild in intensity. Clinically and statistically significant improvements in tear production and ocular surface integrity were observed in subjects treated with OTX-101 0.09% for DED. The safety and efficacy results support the continued development of OTX-101 as a treatment for DED. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>