<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">435</field>
<field name="content">Endothelial keratoplasty for corneal endothelial dystrophy in a dog.,&quot;To determine the prevalence of posterior segment manifestations among consecutive patients with pathological myopia attending our University Hospital general ophthalmology clinic and their association with age, refractive error, axial length and each other. Patients diagnosed with pathological myopia underwent full ophthalmological examination, optical coherence tomography, fluorescein angiography, and ocular ultrasonography. Manifestations detected were recorded for each eye and their prevalence and association with age, refractive error, axial length and each other was determined. A total of 127 eyes of 77 patients with pathological myopia were examined. The most prevalent manifestation was peripheral retinal lesions, found in 63.8% of examined eyes, followed by tigroid fundus, found in 59.1%. Peripheral lesions were significantly associated with more myopia (P = 0.02) and longer axial length (P = 0.046). The commonest peripheral lesion was white without pressure, found in 37.8% of eyes. Lattice degeneration was found in 11.8% and snail track degeneration in 4.7% and were not associated with degree of myopia or axial length. Diffuse chorioretinal atrophy was present in 40.9% of eyes, while patchy atrophy was present in 18.9%. Macular holes were present in 4.7% of eyes and were significantly associated with foveoschisis (P = 0.035) and retinal detachment (P = 0.003), while foveoschisis was present in 5.5% and was significantly associated with older age (P = 0.012), longer axial length (P = 0.010) and patchy chorioretinal atrophy (P = 0.024). Retinal detachment was found in 6.3% of eyes and retinal breaks in 4.7%. Posterior staphyloma was detected in 33.1% and lacquer cracks and choroidal neovascular membranes in 6.3% of eyes. The prevalence of pathological myopia manifestations may differ between different populations. This may be due to the multiple genetic and environmental factors involved which may result in a variable natural history of the condition among different populations. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>