<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">450</field>
<field name="content">[Efficacy of 99mTc-DTPA orbital SPECT/CT on the evaluation of lacrimal gland inflammation in patients with thyroid associated ophthalmopathy].,&quot;This study aimed to evaluate the long-term efficacy and safety of infliximab (IFX) and cyclosporine (CsA) combination therapy for refractory uveoretinitis in Behet&apos;s disease (BD). The study involved a retrospective review of the medical records of 11 patients with Behet&apos;s uveoretinitis refractory to conventional treatment who had been treated with IFX+CsA combination therapy. The frequency of ocular inflammatory attacks and a Behet&apos;s disease ocular attack score 24 (BOS24) were used as indices for the evaluation of efficacy during each 6-month period prior to and following initiation of therapy. For the assessment of safety, adverse events (AEs) were recorded throughout the treatment period. The patients had received IFX+CsA combination therapy for 5.62.3 years. The frequency of ocular attacks per 6-month period decreased markedly from 2.91.6 during the baseline period to 0.60.9 during months 1-6, 0.50.9 during months 7-12, 0.30.5 during months 13-18, 0.30.7 during months 19-24, and 0.00.0 thereafter (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;=0.003). The BOS24 score per ocular attack significantly decreased from 5.22.4 during the baseline period to 1.52.1 during months 1-6, 1.73.1 during months 7-12, 1.62.9 during months 13-18, and 0.41.0 during months 19-24 (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;=0.002). No serious AEs were observed, with the exception of urinary tract infection and cataract progression. Two patients exhibited transient elevation of the serum creatinine level, which was normalized following a reduction in the dose of CsA. For refractory Behet&apos;s uveoretinitis, IFX+CsA combination therapy offers a promising treatment option as it appears to have an acceptable safety profile and can reduce the frequency and severity of ocular inflammatory attacks over a long period of time. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>