<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">461</field>
<field name="content">Optic nerve involvement in ocular toxoplasmosis: 12 year data from a tertiary referral center in Turkey.,&quot;Reports on autosomal recessive optic atrophy (arOA) are sparse and so far, only one gene has been specifically associated with non-syndromic arOA, namely TMEM126A. To date, all reports of pathogenic TMEM126A variants are from affected individuals of Maghrebian origin, who all carry an identical nonsense variant. Here we report two novel variants in the TMEM126A gene from non-Maghreb individuals, both found in affected individuals with an arOA phenotype. We report three affected individuals from two families. The proband of family A, a 24-year-old Turkish woman, was diagnosed with visual loss in early childhood but a diagnosis of optic atrophy was only made at 14years. A diagnostic gene panel revealed a splice donor variant (c.86+2T&gt;C) in homozygous state in the TMEM126A gene. Analysis of this variant based on RNA from whole blood revealed a single aberrant transcript lacking exon 2, presumably representing a functional null allele. Two siblings from family B, a 16-year old Iraqi girl and her 14-year old brother, were diagnosed with optic atrophy in early childhood. A missense variant p.(S36L) in the TMEM126A gene was identified in homozygous state in a gene panel-based diagnostic setting in both siblings. This missense variant is ultra rare in the general population, affects a highly evolutionarily conserved amino acid and segregates with the disease within the family. The three probands reported in this study had a relatively mild clinical course without any evidence of a syndromic (e.g. neurological) comorbidity, which is in line with previous studies. We provide additional evidence for the implication of biallelic pathogenic TMEM126A variants in arOA. Our findings extend both the mutational spectrum and geographic presence of TMEM126A in arOA. Screening of the entire gene should be considered in affected individuals presenting with features resembling arOA and also from non-Maghrebian descent. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>