<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">465</field>
<field name="content">Evaluation of corneal layers and anterior sclera in patients with primary Sjgren&apos;s syndrome.,&quot;To investigate anatomical/functional changes after oral eplerenone therapy for chronic central serous chorioretinopathy (CCSC) in successfully treated eyes and fellow eyes and assess timing of foveal subretinal fluid (SRF) resolution. Twenty-one eyes of 21 patients suffering from CCSC with monolateral foveal SRF successfully treated with oral eplerenone were enrolled in this retrospective study (group 1). The fellow eyes (21 eyes; group 2), healthy or affected by CCSC, without foveal SRF were considered in the analysis. A control healthy group was enrolled as well (healthy controls; &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 21). Main outcome measures during follow-up included changes of best corrected visual acuity (BCVA, logMAR), central macular thickness (CMT; m), SRF (m), subfoveal choroidal thickness (SFCT; m), superficial capillary plexus density (SCPD, %), deep capillary plexus density (DCPD, %), and choriocapillaris density (CCD, %) and percentage of eyes showing foveal SRF resolution at different time points. Functional and anatomical parameters significantly improved during the study in group 1. BCVA increased significantly (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001), while CMT, SFCT, and SRF decreased significantly (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001, and &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.037, respectively). SCPD, DCPD, and CCD did not show any statistically significant difference during follow-up. In 71.4% of eyes, resolution of SRF was observed within 60 days and in the remaining 28.6%, at 120 days. In fellow eyes, SFCT decreased significantly (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001), whilst all other parameters did not modify. Eplerenone treatment in chronic CSCR potentially improves recovery of retinal and choroidal morphology as well as visual acuity gain. A complete resolution of foveal SRF was observed in all eyes during a 4-month follow-up, with most eyes healing at 2 months. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>