<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">472</field>
<field name="content">&quot;Long-Term Intravital Imaging of the Cornea, Skin, and Hair Follicle by Multiphoton Microscope.&quot;,&quot;To characterize the clinical features of Sympathetic ophthalmia (SO) and make a comparison between SO and Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada (VKH) disease in Chinese patients. Retrospective case series. A total of 131 consecutive SO and 500 VKH patients randomly selected out of those referred to our uveitis center from April 2008 to June 2018. The history, extraocular and ocular findings, best corrected visual acuity (BCVA), auxiliary examination findings, complications and therapeutic effects were analyzed retrospectively in SO and VKH patients. SO manifested as posterior uveitis (68.8%) within 2 weeks and equal involvement of anterior and posterior segment (44.4%) respectively was observed between 2 weeks to 2 months after disease onset. Two months after disease onset, SO patients showed sunset glow fundus (51.2%) and granulomatous anterior uveitis (27.3%). VKH patients mainly showed posterior uveitis (100%), anterior segment involvement (92.4%) associated with posterior uveitis (84.9%), granulomatous anterior uveitis (97.4%) accompanying sunset glow fundus (91.5%) in the three time periods mentioned above. The frequencies of extraocular manifestations were lower in SO patients (24.4%) as compared to VKH patients (84.8%) (p&lt;0.001). BCVA (LogMAR) of SO patients was improved from 0.680.86 to 0.470.78 (p=0.01), and BCVA of VKH patients was improved from 0.670.79 to 0.240.53 (p&lt;0.001) at 12 months of follow-up. A worse BCVA was noted in SO patients compared with VKH patients after treatment (p=0.003). Kaplan-Meier survival analysis showed that the risk of loss of useful vision in SO patients was significantly higher than that of VKH patients (p&lt;0.001). Chinese SO and VKH patients have a different evolutionary process. The frequency of extraocular manifestations in SO patients is much lower as compared to VKH patients. Visual outcome is worse in SO as compared to VKH. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>