<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">475</field>
<field name="content">Ectopic Ocular Surface Calcification in Patients With Hypophosphatasia Treated With Asfotase Alfa.,&quot;To classify retinal nonperfusion regions (NPR) in patients with diabetic macular edema (DME) and assess the relationship with severity of DME. Prospective, observational case series. Forty eyes of 29 patients with treatment-nave center-involved macular edema secondary to diabetes mellitus were included (The DAVE study, NCT01552408) in this analysis. Ultra-widefield fluorescein angiography (UWF FA) images were transmitted to the Doheny Image Reading Center, where they were corrected using stereographic projection to adjust for peripheral distortion. Two independent, certified graders manually evaluated the NPR and classified the nonperfusion as being associated with leakage, or without leakage. The size of these two subtypes of NPR were computed in mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and assessed across the entire retina and within three concentric retinal zones. The relationship between subtype of NPR and the severity of DME was assessed. In forty eyes with treatment-nave DME, visual acuity was significantly correlated with central macular thickness (CMT) and macular volume (MV). The NPR with leakage was positively correlated with CMT (R=0.408, P=0.009) and MV (R=0.399, P=0.011), whereas the NPR without leakage was negatively correlated with CMT (R=-0.468, P=0.002) and MV (R=-0.473, P=0.002). The NPR with leakage in the posterior region was significantly greater compared to the mid-periphery and the far-periphery (P&lt;0.001), whereas the NPR without leakage was significantly greater in the mid-periphery compared to the far-periphery or the posterior region (P=0.001). In patients with DME, the severity of DME appears to be positively correlated with NPR with leakage, but negatively correlated with NPR without leakage. These findings may have implications for the pathophysiology of DME and the design of protocols for targeted laser in these eyes. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>