<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">493</field>
<field name="content">&quot;ALPK1 missense pathogenic variant in five families leads to ROSAH syndrome, an ocular multisystem autosomal dominant disorder.&quot;,&quot;To assess incidence and risk factors of cataract extraction in patients with primary congenital glaucoma, surgical outcome, and complications. Retrospective cohort study, in which 108 patients with primary congenital glaucoma were included. Data collected were need for cataract extraction and at what age, intraocular pressure at diagnosis of primary congenital glaucoma, required antiglaucomatous surgeries, possible mutation in the CYP1B1 gene, and final visual acuity. Among the patients who required cataract extraction were visual acuity, intraocular pressure, and complications, evaluated preoperatively and postoperatively. The data were analysed with STATA. A total of 198 eyes of 108 patients were included, with a median follow-up of 8years (range: 5-53). In all, 32 eyes (16.2%) of 24 patients (22%) required cataract extraction. The median age for cataract extraction was 12.94years (interquartile range: 2.42-22). The main identified risk factors associated with cataract extraction were antiglaucomatous surgeries (hazard ratio 1.48, p&lt;0.001) and valvular implant (hazard ratio 2.78, p&lt;0.001). Lens was implanted in 30/32 eyes and the main complications were intraocular pressure decontrol ( n=13), capsular fibrosis ( n=7), corneal decompensation ( n=4), lens subluxation ( n=4), and endophthalmitis ( n=1). Visual acuity improvement was observed after cataract extraction in 66.67% of eyes. There is a high incidence of cataract surgery in patients with primary congenital glaucoma, but generally outside of pediatric age. A greater risk of cataract extraction was identified in those patients with a greater number of antiglaucomatous surgeries, especially after valvular implantation. Despite the high rate of complications related to cataract extraction in primary congenital glaucoma, good visual improvement was observed after surgery. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>