<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">503</field>
<field name="content">Natural history of dry eye disease: Perspectives from inter-ethnic comparison studies.,&quot;&lt;b&gt;Introduction&lt;/b&gt; Bilateral simultaneous endoscopic dacryocystorhinostomy (endo-DCR) has received little attention in the literature, thus many surgeons continue to address bilateral nasolacrimal duct obstruction at two stages, rather than in the same setting. &lt;b&gt;Objective&lt;/b&gt; To evaluate the feasibility and the outcome of simultaneous bilateral Endo-DCR and its impact on the quality of life of the patients. &lt;b&gt;Methods&lt;/b&gt; We have conducted a retrospective analysis of patients who underwent bilateral simultaneous endo-DCR between March 2013 and February 2017 at our tertiary care institution. The reviewed data included clinical presentation; operative details; success rate; pre and postoperative evaluation of the symptoms of the patients, using the Nasolacrimal Duct Obstruction Symptom Score Questionnaire; satisfaction of the patients, and improvement in the quality of life, assessed by the Glasgow Benefit Inventory (GBI) questionnaire. &lt;b&gt;Results&lt;/b&gt; Out of 128 cases in which endo-DCRs were performed, 13 were bilateral (26 sides). Postoperative success was documented in 24 of the 26 sides (92.3%), with a mean follow-up duration of 16.2 months. The two failed sides were reported in the same case. The preoperative symptom score ranged between 12 and 80 (meanstandard deviation [SD]: 38.2315.7). The postoperative symptom score was significantly lower (meanSD: 5.412.9). The success rates in unilateral and bilateral cases were comparable, with no statistically significant difference. A notable improvement in the quality of life of the patients was also reported, with a mean GBI score of 81.3812.37. &lt;b&gt;Conclusion&lt;/b&gt; Our results support that a simultaneous bilateral endo-DCR is a safe procedure that offers a high success rate, spares the patient from the stress of a second surgery, provides the patient with a bilateral resolution of the symptoms, and confers an immediate improvement in the quality of life of the patients. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>