<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">513</field>
<field name="content">Determination of a No Observable Effect Level for Endotoxin Following a Single Intravitreal Administration to Cynomolgus Monkeys.,&quot;Reoperation after decompressive craniectomy (DC) in patients with traumatic brain injury (TBI) remains a dilemma and the risk factors are to be identified. The aim of the current study was to determine the determinants and risk factors of reoperation after DC in patients with TBI. This retrospective case-controlled study was conducted during a 4-year period from September 2013 to October 2017 in a level I trauma center affiliated with Shiraz University of Medical Sciences in southern Iran. We included all the adult (18 years) patients with TBI who underwent primary or secondary DC in our center during the study period. Those who underwent reoperation were compared to those who underwent DC only regarding the demographic findings, clinical features and neuroimaging findings. A univariate and multivariate logistic regression analysis was performed to determine the determining factors of reoperation. Overall we included 371 patients with mean age of 36.4514.18 years. Among the patients there were 325 (87.6%) men and 46 (12.4%) women. The reoperation in patients undergoing DC due to TBI was associated with primary DC (p=0.039) and higher Marshall grade (p=0.027). Those who underwent reoperation after DC for TBI had significantly higher ICU (p=0.007) and hospital LOS (p=0.001) and lower 6-month GOSE (p=0.010). Age (p&lt;0.001), GCS (p&lt;0.001) and pupils (p=0.027) were predictors of outcome in reoperation group. Reoperation in primary DC group was associated with pupil reactivity (p=0.002) and number of episodes with INR above 1.5 (p=0.037) Conclusion: Reoperation after DC for TBI is associated with primary DC, and Marshall grade. The reoperation after DC is associated with worse outcome and longer ICU and hospital stay. The age, GCS and pupil reactivity are the main predictors of outcome in those with reoperation after DC for TBI. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>