<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">514</field>
<field name="content">Prevalence and Associations of Posterior Segment Manifestations in a Cohort of Egyptian Patients with Pathological Myopia.,&quot;To evaluate the neurodevelopmental and ocular developmental outcomes in premature children who have undergone intravitreal bevacizumab injection (IVB) for treatment of type 1 retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) DESIGN: Prospective case-control study SUBJECTS: We enrolled 3 groups of premature patients: premature children who had no history of ROP (Group 0), premature children with history of ROP without treatment (Group 1), and premature children who had received a single IVB (0.625 mg) for treatment of ROP (Group 2). Ocular developmental assessment, including cycloplegic refractometry, axial length and Cardiff acuity, and neurodevelopmental assessment via the Bayley Scales of Infant and Toddler Development, Third Edition (Bayley-III), were performed at the age of 1 to 3 years, and were compared between groups. Ocular developmental outcomes and Bayley-III scores RESULTS: A total of 148 patients (85 boys and 63 girls) were included. The mean age of assessment was 1.49  0.59 years. Group 0 patients had significantly higher gestational age (GA), birth weight, and Apgar scores compared to Group 1 and Group 2. There were no significant differences between Group 1 and Group 2 in demographics or systemic risk factors except for lower GA in Group 2. The cylindrical power was significantly larger in Group 1 and Group 2 compared to Group 0. The spherical equivalent was significantly more myopic and the Cardiff acuity was significantly poorer in Group 2 than in Group 0. There were no significant differences between Group 1 and Group 2 in refractive status, axial length or Cardiff acuity. Neurodevelopmental assessment using Bayley-III showed no significant difference among the three groups in any aspect after adjusting for GA and other systemic risk factors. The risks for poor neurodevelopmental outcomes were also not significantly different. At the mean age of 1.5 years, children with prior history of IVB (Group 2) have similar refractive and visual outcomes and similar neurodevelopmental outcomes compared to premature patients with ROP without requirement of treatment (Group 1), although there is a possibility that a small but clinically significant difference may not have been detected in the current study. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>