<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">616</field>
<field name="content">In vivo confocal microscopy of the inflamed anterior segment: a review of clinical and research applications.,&quot;To evaluate the safety and efficacy of the Port Delivery System with ranibizumab (PDS) for neovascular age-related macular degeneration (nAMD) treatment. Phase 2, multicenter, randomized, active treatment-controlled clinical trial. Patients diagnosed with nAMD within 9 months who had received  2 prior anti-vascular endothelial growth factor intravitreal injections and were responsive to treatment. Patients were randomized 3:3:3:2 to receive the PDS filled with ranibizumab 10 mg/mL, 40 mg/mL, and 100 mg/mL formulations or monthly intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg injections. Time to first implant refill assessed when the last enrolled patient completed the month 9 visit (primary efficacy endpoint); improvement in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) and central foveal thickness (CFT); and safety. The primary analysis population was 220 patients, with 58, 62, 59, and 41 patients in the PDS 10 mg/mL, 40 mg/mL, and 100 mg/mL arms and the monthly intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg arm, respectively. Median time to first implant refill was 8.7, 13.0, and 15.0 months in the PDS 10 mg/mL, 40 mg/mL, and 100 mg/mL arms, respectively. At month 9, the adjusted mean BCVA change from baseline was 3.2, 0.5, +5.0, and +3.9 Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study letters in the PDS 10 mg/mL, 40 mg/mL, and 100 mg/mL arms and the monthly intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg arms, respectively. At month 9, the adjusted mean CFT change from baseline was similar in the PDS 100 mg/mL and the monthly intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg arms. The optimized PDS implant insertion and refill procedures were generally well tolerated. After surgical procedure optimization, postoperative vitreous hemorrhage rate was 4.5% (7/157; 1 event classified as serious). There was no evidence of implant clogging. In the phase 2 Ladder trial, the PDS was generally well tolerated and demonstrated a dose response across multiple endpoints in patients with nAMD. The PDS 100 mg/mL arm had visual and anatomic outcomes comparable with monthly intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg injections, but with a reduced total number of ranibizumab treatments. The PDS has the potential to reduce treatment burden in nAMD while maintaining vision. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>