<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">626</field>
<field name="content">Extracellular ATP activates P2X7R-NF-B (p65) pathway to promote the maturation of bone marrow-derived dendritic cells of mice.,&quot;Numerous studies have reported the efficacy of fenofibrate for patients with diabetic retinopathy (DRP). No systematic review has, however, addressed its efficacy for DRP. Thus, this systematic review will firstly evaluate the efficacy and safety of fenofibrate for patients with DRP. This study will search the following databases: PUMBED, EMBASE, CINAHI, ACMD, CENTRAL, CBM, CNKI, VIP, and WANGFANG, along with grey literature from inception to the present. We will accept randomized controlled trials on evaluating the efficacy and safety of fenofibrate for DRP. The primary outcome is the progression of DRP. The secondary outcomes are vision loss, development of diabetic macular edema, aggravation of hard exudates, quality of life, and any adverse events. Methodological quality of each included study will be assessed by using Cochrane Collaboration risk of bias tool. In addition, Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation tool will also be used to evaluate the overall strength of the evidence. Two independent reviewers will conduct all procedures of study selection, data extraction, and methodological assessment. Any disagreements will be consulted with a third reviewer. RevMan 5.3 software will be used to pool data and to carry out the meta-analysis if it is possible. In present study, we anticipate to find a considerable number of published studies presenting evidence on efficacy and safety of fenofibrate for DRP. The findings of this systematic review will provide latest evidence of fenofibrate for patients with DRP. The findings of this scoping review will be disseminated in print, conferences, or by peer-reviewed journals. No ethical approval is needed for this systematic review, because it is a literature-based study. PROSPERO CRD42019121869. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>