<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">63</field>
<field name="content">Mutant RAMP2 causes primary open-angle glaucoma via the CRLR-cAMP axis.,&quot;It was the aim of this study to analyse the refractive outcome of toric intraocular lens (t-IOL) implantation guided by a newly developed method of photographic alignment. Fourteen eyes of 10 patients (6 females, 4 males, age 63.46.7 (40.6-68.0) years [mean1SD (range)]) were included in this retrospective study. All eyes received an Oculentis Tplus LS-313 (Oculentis, Berlin, Germany) t-IOL after standard phacoemusification (n=4) or femtocataract laser-assisted surgery (n=10). Image-guided t-IOL alignment included: (1) calculation of t-IOL parameters (combination of different biometric methods) and plotting a layout drawing of the target lens position, (2) capture of an anterior segment slit lamp photograph in the upright position, (3) superposition of the photographs by the t-IOL target plot and a gradual scale, (4) drawing of marker lines on the photograph and removal of the IOL target coordinates, (5) transfer of the final image to a tablet PC, and (6) marking of the target axis at the corneal limbus with an ink pen in the surgical room. Preoperative corneal astigmatism was 2.500.97 (1.38-4.34) diopters (D) (mean1SD, range). In all eyes, intraoperative alignment could easily be performed using the photographic target layout. Surgical interventions and postoperative follow-up were without complications in all cases. Residual postoperative astigmatism was 0.160.24 (0.00-0.75) D (p&lt;0.001 compared to preoperative astigmatism). In 64% of patients, residual subjective astigmatism was zero, in 93% 0.5 D, and in 100% 0.75 D. Postoperative uncorrected logMAR visual acuity (0.050.07, range 0.00-0.20) and best-corrected visual acuity (0.030.05, 0.00-0.10) were significantly better (each p&lt;0.001) than best-corrected preoperative visual acuity (0.210.14, 0.00-0.49). Results of this clinical series clearly indicate that the newly developed photographically guided technique of toric lens alignment leads to highly accurate postoperative results for astigmatic correction. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>