<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">668</field>
<field name="content">Cluster analysis of computerized visual field and optical coherence tomography-ganglion cell complex defects in high intraocular pressure patients or early stage glaucoma.,&quot;To observe the effects of acupuncture combined with phacoemulsification for cataract with glaucoma. Sixty-eight patients with cataract and angle-closure glaucoma were randomly divided into an observation group and a control group, 34 cases in each one. The patients in the control group were treated with phacoemulsification. Based on the treatment in the control group, the patients in the observation group were treated with &lt;i&gt;tuina&lt;/i&gt; and acupuncture at acupoints around eyes; the treatment was given once every other day, and 15-day treatment constituted a course, and 2 courses (60 days) were given. The intraocular pressure (IOP), visual acuity, pain severity, aqueous outflow (F value) and clinical symptoms were observed in the two groups before treatment and after 1 d, 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment. The IOP after 1 d, 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment in the observation group was lower than that in the control group (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05), while the visual acuity after 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment in the observation group was higher than that in the control group (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). Compared before treatment, the IOP was significantly decreased after 1 d, 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment in the two groups, and the visual acuity was significantly increased after 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment in the two groups (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). The pain scores and F value after 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment in the observation group were lower than those in the control group (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). Compared before treatment, the pain scores and F value after 7 d, 30 d and 60 d of treatment were significantly reduced in the two groups (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). After 60 d of treatment, the number of patients who presented general clinical symptoms in the observation group was significantly lower than that in the control group (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). Based on phacoemulsification, acupuncture and &lt;i&gt;tuina&lt;/i&gt; could significantly reduce the IOP and F value, relieve pain and improve visual acuity in patients with cataract and glaucoma. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>