<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">670</field>
<field name="content">Time for a makeover-cosmetics regulation in the United States.,&quot;To analyze the effects of intradermal needling for pain and tear film stability in patients after pterygium excision. A total of 76 patients (98 affected eyes) with primary pterygium were randomly divided into an observation group (38 cases, 53 affected eyes) and a control group (38 cases, 45 affected eyes).In the control group, only pterygium resection was performed, in the observation group, intradermal needling after pterygium resection was applied at Cuanzhu (BL 2), Yuyao (EX-HN 4), Taiyang (EX-HN 5), Sibai (ST 2), Hegu (LI 4), removed after 24 h and changed three times a week. The pain level of 3 days after surgery, dry eye symptoms, the basic tear secretion test (Schirmer-), and the tear-break time (BUT) changes before surgery, 2 weeks after surgery and 4 weeks after surgery were compared between the two groups, and the clinical efficacy was evaluated. The pain level of 3 days after surgery in the observation group was significantly lower than that in the control group (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). The dry eye symptom scores at 2 weeks and 4 weeks after surgery in the two groups were significantly lower than those before surgery (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05), and the dry eye symptom scores in the observation group were significantly lower than those in the control group (both &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). The Schirmer- test at 2 weeks and 4 weeks after surgery was significantly prolonged than that before surgery(all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05), and the Schirmer- test in the observation group was significantly longer than that in the control group (both &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). The BUT at 2 weeks and 4 weeks after surgery in the two groups was significantly longer than that before surgery (all &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05), and the BUT in the observation group was significantly longer than that in the control group (both &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). The total effective rate in the observation group was 89.5% (34/38), which was higher than 71.1% (27/38) in the control group (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.05). Intradermal needling can effectively reduce the pain level of patients after pterygium resection, improve dry eye symptoms, promote the secretion of tears and improve the tear film stability. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>