<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">713</field>
<field name="content">Association of Vision Loss With Hospital Use and Costs Among Older Adults.,&quot;Objective To investigate which bone age assessment techniques are utilized by radiologists in Pakistan to determine skeletal age in three defined age groups: less than one year, one to three years and three to 18 years. We also assessed the perceived confidence in skeletal age assessments made by respondents using their chosen bone age assessment technique, within each defined age group. Materials and methods A cross-sectional survey was conducted among 147 practicing radiologists in Pakistan. A pre-validated survey form was adopted from a similar study conducted amongst members of theSociety for Pediatric Radiology. The survey collected demographic information, choice of bone age assessment technique in each age group and confidence of bone age assessments in each age group. Results The hand-wrist method of Greulich and Pyle was used by 87.5% of respondents when assessing bone age in infants (less than one year), followed by Gilsanz-Ratibhand bone age method (7.3%). In children aged one to three years, Greulich and Pyle methodwas chosen by 85.7% of respondents, followed by Gilsanz-Ratibhand bone age method (6.1%) and the Hoerr, Pyle, Francis\&apos;Radiographic Atlas of Skeletal Development of the Foot and Ankle (3.1%). In children, older than three years, the Greulich and Pyle technique was used by 83.7% of respondents. This was followed by Gilsanz-Ratibhand bone age method (5.8%) and the Hoerr, Pyle, Francis\&apos;Radiographic Atlas of Skeletal Development of the Foot and Ankle (3.8%). 26.4% were &quot;&quot;very confident&quot;&quot; in bone age assessments conducted among infants. In children aged one to three years, 38.1% were &quot;&quot;very confident&quot;&quot;. In children, greater than three years, 48.6% were &quot;&quot;very confident&quot;&quot; in their chosen technique. Conclusion Greulich and Pyle is the dominant method for bone age assessments in all age groups, however, confidence in its application among infants and young children is low. It is recommended that clear recommendations be developed for bone age assessments in this age group alongside incorporation of indigenous standards of bone age assessments based on a representative sample of healthy native children. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>