<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">719</field>
<field name="content">Current screening practice in patients under long-term hydroxychloroquine medication in Taiwan: A nationwide population-based cohort study.,&quot;Diabetic retinopathy (DR) is a chronic and progressive complication of diabetes mellitus. DR impairs sight due to neuronal and vascular dysfunction in the retina. It is critical to investigate the pathogenesis of DR to develop effective treatment. In the present study, a streptozotocin (STZ)-induced diabetic rat model was constructed and the expression of microRNA (miR)-204-5p and vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) were determined. Immunohistochemistry, reverse transcription-quantitative polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR) and western blotting were employed to detect the effects of miR-204-5p on the expression of microtubule-associated protein 1 light chain 3 (LC3B). RT-qPCR analysis demonstrated that miR-204-5p and VEGF were significantly upregulated in the retina tissue of diabetic rats compared with the control group (P&lt;0.01). Immunohistochemistry and western blotting revealed that the protein expression levels of LC3B-II and the ratio of LC3B-II/LC3B-I were significantly suppressed in the diabetes group compared with the control (P&lt;0.01). In retinal tissues, anti-miR-204-5p treatment significantly enhanced the protein expression levels of LC3B-II and the ratio of LC3B-II/LC3B-I and these levels were significantly reduced in response to miR-204-5p mimic treatment compared with the negative miR control (P&lt;0.01). In rat retinal endothelial cells isolated from diabetic rats, anti-miR-204-5p treatment increased the number of autophagic vacuoles, and significantly promoted LC3B-II expression and the LC3B-II/LC3B-I ratio compared with the negative control (P&lt;0.01). The results of the present study revealed that miR-204-5p downregulated the expression of LC3B-II to inhibit autophagy in DR. Therefore, miR-204-5p may be considered as a novel effective therapeutic target during the development of DR. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>