<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">724</field>
<field name="content">Establishment of vestibular function multimodality platform.,&quot;To assess the utility and safety of implanting two second-generation trabecular micro-bypass stents following cataract surgery in eyes with mild to advanced glaucoma or ocular hypertension (OHT). Retrospective study of iStent&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;inject trabecular micro-bypass implantation with cataract surgery by five surgeons at five sites in Australia. Eyes had mild to advanced glaucoma (predominantly primary open-angle, appositional angle-closure, or pseudoexfoliative glaucoma) or OHT and cataract requiring surgery. Effectiveness measures included intraocular pressure (IOP); medication burden; and proportions of eyes with no medications, 2 medications, stable or decreased medications vs preoperative, and IOP 18 mmHg. Safety measures included visual acuity, cup-to-disc ratio (CDR), visual field (VF), complications, adverse events, and secondary surgical interventions. Patients have been followed for 12 months, and follow-up is ongoing. Of the 290 total eyes that underwent surgery, 165 eyes had 12-month outcomes at the time of data collection and are included in this report. In these eyes, mean Month 12 IOP reduced by 23.2% from 18.275.41 mmHg preoperatively to 14.042.98 mmHg (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.001), with 95.8% of eyes achieving Month 12 IOP of 18 mmHg vs 60.6% preoperatively. Mean number of medications at 12 months decreased by 71.5%, 0.470.95 vs 1.651.28 preoperatively; 76.4% of eyes were on zero medications vs 17.6% preoperatively (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.001); 14.5% of eyes were on 2 medications vs 46.7% preoperatively (&lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;&lt;0.001); and 98.2% of eyes maintained or reduced medications vs their preoperative regimen. Favorable safety included no stent-related intraoperative complications; limited and transient postoperative adverse events; and stable CDR, VF, and visual acuity. Three eyes with more advanced disease underwent additional glaucoma surgeries. iStent inject implantation with cataract surgery significantly and safely reduced medications and IOP in eyes with various types and severities of glaucoma within a multicenter, multi-provider, real-life setting. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>