<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">750</field>
<field name="content">Exploring patients&apos; expectations and preferences of glaucoma surgery outcomes to facilitate healthcare delivery and inform future glaucoma research.,&quot;This study aimed to analyse microstructure data on the density and orientation of collagen fibrils in whole eye globes and to propose an effective method for the preparation of data for use in numerical simulations of the eye&apos;s biomechanical performance. Wide-angle X-ray scattering was applied to seven healthy ex-vivo human eyes. Each eye was dissected into an anterior and a posterior cup, and radial incisions were used to flatten the tissue before microstructure characterisation. A method was developed to use the microstructure data obtained for the dissected tissue to build realistic 3D maps of fibril density and orientation covering the whole eye globe. At the central cornea, 61.52.3% of fibrils were aligned within 45 sectors surrounding the two orthogonal directions. In contrast, more than one-third of the total fibril content was concentrated along the circumferential direction at the limbus (37.02.4%) and around the optic nerve head (34.82.1%). The insertion locations of the four recti muscles exhibited a preference in the meridional direction near the equator (38.63.9%). There was also a significant difference in fibril density between the limbus and other regions (ratio = 1.910.45, p &lt;0.01 at the central cornea and ratio = 0.800.21, p &lt;0.01 at the posterior pole). Characterisation of collagen fibril density and orientation across the whole ocular surface has been possible but required the use of a technique that involved tissue dissection and hence caused tissue damage. The method presented in this paper aimed to minimise the effect of dissection on the quality of obtained data and was successful in identifying fibril distribution trends that were compatible with earlier studies, which concentrated on localised areas of the ocular globe. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>