<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">761</field>
<field name="content">Application of SPF moisturisers is inferior to sunscreens in coverage of facial and eyelid regions.,&quot;To characterize retinal morphology differences among different types of choroidal neovascularization and visual function changes at the onset of exudative age-related macular degeneration. In a post hoc analysis of a prospective clinical study, 1,097 fellow eyes from subjects with choroidal neovascularization in the study eye enrolled in the HARBOR trial were evaluated. The onset of exudation was diagnosed on monthly optical coherence tomography by two masked graders. At conversion as well as 1 month earlier, pigment epithelial detachment, intraretinal cystoid fluid, subretinal fluid, subretinal hyperreflective material, as well as ellipsoid zone and external limiting membrane loss were quantitatively analyzed. Hyperreflective foci, retinal pigment epithelial defects, haze and vitreoretinal interface status were evaluated qualitatively. Main outcome measures included visual acuity and rates of morphologic features at conversion and 1 month earlier. New-onset exudation was detected in 92 eyes. One month before conversion, hyperreflective foci, pigment epithelial detachment, retinal pigment epithelial defects, and haze were present in the majority of eyes. At the onset of exudation, the volumes of intraretinal cystoid fluid, subretinal fluid, subretinal hyperreflective material and pigment epithelial detachment, and the areas of external limiting membrane and ellipsoid zone loss significantly increased. The mean vision loss was -2.2 letters. Pathognomonic patterns of the different choroidal neovascularization types were already apparent 1 month before conversion. Characteristic choroidal neovascularization-associated morphological changes are preceding disease conversion, while vision loss at the onset of exudation is minimal. Individual lesion types are related to specific changes in optical coherence tomography morphology already before the time of conversion. Our findings may help to elucidate the pathophysiology of neovascular age-related macular degeneration and support the diagnosis of imminent disease conversion. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>