<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">77</field>
<field name="content">Thermal Ablation in the Management of Colorectal Cancer Patients with Oligometastatic Liver Disease.,"<b>Background</b>Image-guided thermal ablation can be used for the treatment of medically inoperable primary and metastatic lung cancer. These techniques are based on the heating up or freezing (cryoablation) of a volume of tissue around a percutaneous applicator that induces necrosis of the tumor. <b>Method</b>The English-language literature concerning thermal ablation of the lung was reviewed. Radiofrequency ablation (RFA) is the most widely performed and investigated of these techniques. Microwave ablation (MWA) represents a relatively new alternative that shares the same indications and is conducted in a very similar fashion as RFA. It has been experimentally and clinically shown that MWA produces larger, more spherical ablation zones over shorter periods of time compared to RFA. Seven different MWA systems are available in Europe and the USA with significant differences in the size and shape of the produced ablation zones. <b>Results</b>The types of complications caused by MWA and their rates of occurrence are very similar to those caused by RFA. The local progression rates after MWA of lung malignancies vary between 0% and 34% and are similar to those in the RFA literature. <b>Conclusion</b>Despite technical improvements, the current generation of MWA systems has comparable clinical outcomes to those of RFA. <b>Key Points</b>  MWA is a safe technique that should be considered one ofthe treatment options for medically inoperable lung tumors.  As thermal ablations of lung tumors are becoming more frequent, radiologists should be acquainted with the post-ablation imaging characteristics.  Although MWA has some theoretical advantages over RFA, the clinical outcomes are similar. <b>Citation Format</b>  Vogl TJ, Nour-Eldin NA, Albrecht MH etal. Thermal Ablation of Lung Tumors: Focus on Microwave Ablation. Fortschr Rntgenstr 2017; 189: 828-843."
</field>
</doc>
</add>