<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">786</field>
<field name="content">Suboptimal T-cell Therapy Drives a Tumor Cell Mutator Phenotype That Promotes Escape from Frontline Treatment.,&quot;Introduction The correlation between corneal curvature and central corneal thickness (CCT), with ocular parameters like axial length and refraction, remains elusive. The various ocular biometric parameters are interdependent and their correlation varies with the population studied. A comprehensive study is required for a better understanding of the ocular biometric properties of Indian eyes. Methodology This is a prospective study done in 156 subjects. Subjects with clear lens and clear cornea were included in the study. Those with corneal opacity, cataract, pregnancy,and diabetes were excluded. Cycloplegic refraction, autokeratometry (Potex, ultrasonic auto keratometer), central corneal thickness (ultrasonic pachymeter), and axial length (Sonomed) were done in all subjects. Subjects were divided into two groups based on refraction, for an analysis of parameters. Group one included subjects with refraction of +3 diopters (D) to -2.99D and group two with subjects with &gt; -3D refraction. Results With anincreasing axial length and myopic refraction, the corneal curvature tends to be steeper. The average CCT of subjects in group one and group two were 530.34 microns and 542.63 microns, respectively. Subjects with refraction more than 10 diopters or axial length more than 25 mm had a mean CCT of 525.25 microns. Subjects with myopic refraction between 3 diopters and 10 diopters had a mean CCT of 551.32 microns. Conclusion Increase in corneal power is associated with increasing myopic refraction. Steeper corneal curvature is correlated with increasing axial length and thinner corneas. The mean CCT was 533.87 microns with a standard deviation (SD) of 40.02. Axial myopia is associated with an increase in corneal thickness. These ocular biometric findings have crucial implications in refractive surgeries. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>