<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">8</field>
<field name="content">&quot;Trans-Arterial Embolization of Renal Cell Carcinoma prior to Percutaneous Ablation: Technical Aspects, Institutional Experience, and Brief Review of the Literature.&quot;,&quot;We aimed to assess the safety and effectiveness of transarterial embolization (TAE) prior to percutaneous cryoablation (PCA) in the management of renal cell carcinoma (RCC) compared with PCA alone using a propensity score matching analysis to minimize confounding factors. A retrospective review of all PCAs performed for renal masses identified 9 patients who underwent TAE prior to PCA. These patients were matched in a 2:1 ratio with patients who underwent PCA only using age, gender, and tumor size to create the propensity score model for matching. Other demographic, clinical, and outcomes data were collected. The TAE+PCA group included 5 males and 4 females with a mean age of 67.9 years and mean tumor diameter of 51.7 mm. The PCA only group included 11 males and 7 females with a mean age of 66.8 years and mean tumor diameter of 46.2 mm. No significant differences in these propensity score matched characteristics were identified. Further, the groups had no significant differences in tumor geometry (P = 0.831), R.E.N.A.L. nephrometry scores (P = 0.144), or comorbidity indices (P = 0.392). TAE was technically successful and without complication in all cases. PCA was technically successful in 8 of 9 patients in the TAE+PCA group and in 14 of 18 patients in the PCA only group (P = 0.483). No significant differences in the rate of complications (P = 0.483), change in eGFR (P = 0.691), or change in hematocrit (P = 0.152) were identified between the two groups. TAE of RCC prior to PCA is safe and technically feasible; however, no objective benefits over PCA alone were identified by propensity score matching analysis. Due to small sample size and limitations of the study, no definite conclusions should be drawn. Larger, prospective studies of this therapeutic approach are warranted.&quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>