<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">814</field>
<field name="content">Disease-associated mutations of claudin-19 disrupt retinal neurogenesis and visual function.,&quot;Lacrycon&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a preservative-free hypotonic artificial tear for the treatment of dry eye syndrome containing hyaluronic acid, carbomer, and glycerol. Lacrycon has been used for many years; this is the first comprehensive review of clinical efficacy and tolerability. Eight clinical studies (1992-2013) were reviewed. Comparators included phosphate-buffered saline (Phase I) and active controls (Phase II: Lacrisol; Phase III: Gel-larmes, Lacrisol, Hyalistil&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Vismed&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or the currently prescribed tear substitute). Administration schedules varied from 3 to 8 instillations per day for 7 to 84 days, and evaluation timepoints varied between studies. Pre-corneal retention of Lacrycon was 22% better than phosphate-buffered saline in terms of AUC (P=0.048). Patients&apos; evaluation of efficacy was better for Lacrycon than Gel-larmes on Day 15 and 45 (P&lt;0.05) and similar on Day 90 (P&gt;0.05); there was no difference (P&gt;0.05) versus Hyalistil (Day 30) or Vismed (Day 35 and 85). Functional tests were either in favor of Lacrycon (P&lt;0.05) (fluorescein test [versus Gel-larmes/Lacrisol/Hyalistil], tear break-up time [TBUT] and rose Bengal test, Schirmer I test, and tear meniscus [versus Lacrisol]), or there was no difference between treatments (P&gt;0.05) (fluorescein test [versus Vismed], TBUT and rose Bengal test [versus Gel-larmes], Schirmer I test [versus Gel-larmes/Lacrisol/Hyalistil/VisMed], tear meniscus [versus Lacrisol/Hyalistil], Oxford Grading Score, OSDI, van Bijsterveld score, and conjunctival hyperemia [versus Vismed]). Lacrycon was better tolerated than most comparators and had a similar safety profile to Vismed. No comparison showed favored the comparator over Lacrycon. These good efficacy, tolerability and safety data support the use of Lacrycon in dry eye syndrome. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>