<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">824</field>
<field name="content">A novel technique for the surgical management of intraocular lens-capsular bag-capsular tension ring complex dislocation.,&quot;A novel treatment for posterior blepharitis which involves the use of disposable wet wipes imbibed with a solution of terpinen-4-ol and hyaluronic acid (Hy-Ter&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) as well as aloe, natural anti-inflammatories and antiseptics (Blephapad Combo; Novelty Technology Care, Milan, Italy) has been proposed. The aim of this study was to compare the efficacy and safety of treatment with Blephapad Combo with standard treatment. We conducted 4-week, open-label, randomized controlled study with a closed sequential design at the Magna Graecia University of Catanzaro, Italy in which patients aged&gt;40years with symmetrical bilateral posterior blepharitis were enrolled. Each eye represented a single experimental unit. Patients were randomly assigned using a computer-generated randomization list to apply a reusable heated compress to the eyelid of one eye before cleansing the eyelid with the Blephapad Combo wet wipe (Blephapad Combo treatment arm) or to use the standard treatment of applying a wet and warm gauze to the other eye (standard treatment arm), twice daily for 4weeks. The primary endpoint was the percentage change from baseline to week 4 in meibomian gland dysfunction (MGD) grading scale scores. Eighteen patients (9 men; 9 women) with a mean ( standard deviation) age of 66.99.03years were included in the study. Compared with the eye receiving the standard treatment, treatment with Blephapad Combo appeared to improve the MGD total score after 4weeks of treatment (mean change from baseline -29.9 vs. -38.5%). The assessment of the investigators was that in 11 patients the eye treated with Blephapad Combo showed greater benefit, in two patients the eye treated with the standard treatment showed greater benefit and in four patients there was no difference between treatments. Blephapad Combo was well tolerated, with no serious adverse events (AEs) reported. Minor ocular AEs were reported in 44.4 and 38.9% of patients in the Blephard Combo and standard treatment arms, respectively. Treatment with Blephapad Combo was more effective than the standard treatment in ameliorating MGD in patients with posterior blepharitis. Minor ocular AEs events were equally distributed between the two treatments arms. ClinicalTrials.gov identifier: NCT03301844. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>