<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">828</field>
<field name="content">&quot;One-year outcomes following implantation of second-generation trabecular micro-bypass stents in conjunction with cataract surgery for various types of glaucoma or ocular hypertension: multicenter, multi-surgeon study.&quot;,&quot;To report the real-world effectiveness and safety of ranibizumab 0.5 mg in patients with visual impairment due to diabetic macular edema (DME). This is a French, 36-month, multicenter, observational cohort study. Between December 2013 and April 2015, ophthalmologists enrolled diabetic patients aged 18 years with DME-related visual impairment and for whom ranibizumab 0.5 mg was initiated. Here, we present the 12-month results from this cohort. The primary endpoint was the mean change in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA); sample size calculations were based on RESTORE trial data (BCVA mean change = 6.8 letters, preci sion = 0.7 letters). Secondary endpoints included the change in central subfield thickness (CSFT), number of visits, number of injections received, and frequency of ocular and nonocular adverse events and serious adverse events. Between December 2013 and April 2015, a total of 290 patients with DME were enrolled by 84 ophthalmologists; 12-month data are available for 242 patients (due to low recruitment rates, precision was recalculated for 242 evaluable patients: the precision was then of 1.0 letters). Mean age ( standard deviation) was 66.1  11.0 years and 56.6% were male. The mean baseline BCVA and CSFT were 59.2 letters (95% confidence interval [CI] 57.3, 61.0) and 457 m (95% CI: 438, 476), respectively. At month 12, the mean gain in BCVA from baseline was 7.4 letters (95% CI: 5.4, 9.4), with 36.8% of patients with BCVA &gt; 70 letters versus 13.2% at baseline. Mean change in CSFT was -125 m (95% CI: -146, -103). The mean number of ranibizumab injections was 5.1  2.3 over an average of 10.4  3.0 visits. No new safety findings were identified. The BOREAL study confirms the effectiveness and safety of ranibizumab for the treatment of DME-related visual impairment in routine clinical practice with fewer injections than reported in clinical trials. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>