<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">848</field>
<field name="content">Predicting visual outcomes in patients treated with aflibercept for neovascular age-related macular degeneration: Data from a real-world clinical setting.,&quot;This report by a group of UK retina specialists and health professionals considers best practice recommendations for the management of sight-threatening neovascular age-related macular degeneration (nAMD), based on collective experience and expertise in routine clinical practice. The authors provide an update for ophthalmologists, allied healthcare professionals and commissioners on practice principles for optimal patient care and service provision standards. Refinement of care pathways for nAMD has improved access to intravitreal anti-vascular endothelial growth factor therapy but there are still variations in care and reported outcomes between clinic centres. Innovative organisational models of service provision allow providers to better match capacity with increasing demand. The authors review the recent NICE guideline for diagnosis and management of AMD, considerations for switching therapies and stopping treatment and need for regular monitoring of non-affected fellow eyes in patients with unilateral nAMD. Actions for delivery of high-quality care and to improve long-term patient outcomes are discussed. Local pathways need to detail nAMD target time to treat, maintenance of review intervals to ensure proactive treatment regimens are delivered on time and appropriate discharge for patients deemed low risk or no longer benefiting from treatment. Actual visual acuity outcomes achieved and maintenance of the level of vision when disease stability is achieved are considered good measures for judging the quality of care in the treatment of patients with nAMD. Robust community referral pathways must be in place for suspected reactivation of choroidal neovascularisation and rapid referral for second eye involvement. Practical considerations for intravitreal injection therapy are outlined. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>