<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">85</field>
<field name="content">Successful Big Bubble-Assisted Deep Anterior Lamellar Keratoplasty in a Patient with Intracorneal Ring Segments and Previous Corneal Collagen Cross-Linking for Keratoconus.,&quot;The ubiquitin-proteasome system pathway has been recognised as a crucial cellular mechanism for the proper function of photoreceptor cells. In particular, ubiquitin ligases (E3s) recognise and ubiquitinate specific proteins for degradation. The KLHL7 protein (a BTB-Kelch protein) has been found to play an important role in this process. There have been several reports that heterozygous mutations in the &lt;i&gt;KLHL7&lt;/i&gt; gene in adults are responsible for a rare cause of late-onset autosomal dominant retinitis pigmentosa with preservation of central vision and homozygous mutations in two young children, with Crisponi syndrome (CS)/cold-induced sweating syndrome type 1, result in a recessive form of early-onset peripheral retinal dystrophy type changes. The majority of children do not survive through to adulthood. The objective of this study is to report the visual symptoms and signs of two young adults clinically diagnosed with overlapping BOS/Cisproni syndrome, expanding the phenotypic presentation of KLHL7 gene mutations. This is a case report of the ophthalmic findings of two siblings with biallelic KLHL7 gene mutations. Siblings born to a non-consanguineous family and diagnosed with the overlapping clinical phenotype of Bohring-Opitz and and confirmed biallelic KLHL 7 gene mutation by whole exome sequencing were identified. Ophthlamic history and fundal examination was performed and analysed. Both patients had similar retinal findings. The fundus shows confluent hypopigmented/pale yellow lesions in the mid-periphery. The optic disc appears to be pale with a ring of atrophy and vessels appear attenuated. The macular of the younger patient shows a depigmented area around the fovea giving a bull&apos;s-eye appearance while the older sibling shows a fibrotic ring around the fovea suggesting a more advanced pathology. This paper expands the retinal phenotype to include a distinctive maculopathy in a recently described homozygous mutation in the &lt;i&gt;KLHL7&lt;/i&gt; gene in two young adults presenting with features that overlap the Bohring-Opitz syndrome and CS. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>