<add>
<doc>
<field name="doc_id">86</field>
<field name="content">Corneal Endothelial Decompensation after Ocular Chemical Burn: Description of a New Finding.,&quot;Femtosecond laser-assisted cataract surgery (FLACS) decreases the use of energy and provides a more precise capsulorhexis compared with conventional phaco surgery (CPS). The purpose of this study was to examine if the lower energy use in FLACS caused less endothelial cell loss compared with CPS and if there was a difference in refractive predictability between CPS and FLACS. This was a randomised controlled study of 96 patients with a 6-month follow-up comparing one eye surgery by FLACS and the contralateral eye operated by CPS (divide and conquer technique). Both eyes had intraocular aspheric lenses implanted. Uncorrected distance visual acuity, corrected distance visual acuity (CDVA), central corneal endothelial cell count and hexagonality (non-contact endothelial cell microscope) were assessed preoperatively at 40 and at 180 days postoperatively. The mean phaco energies were 6.55 (95% CI 5.43 to 7.66) and 9.77 (95% CI 8.55 to 10.95)U/S (p&lt;0.0001) by FLACS and CPS, respectively. At day 40, the mean endothelial cell loss (ECL) was 344 cells/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (95%CI 245 to 443) by FLACS (12.89%) and 497 cells/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (95%CI 380 to 614) by CPS (18.19%) (p=0.027). At day 180, ECL was 362 cells/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (95%CI 275 to 450) in FLACS (13.56%) and 465 cells/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (95%CI 377 to 554) in CPS (17.03%) (p=0.036).The mean absolute difference from the attempted refraction was 0.43 (95% CI 0.36 to 0.51) dioptres (D) at day 40 and 0.46 D (95% CI 0.39 to 0.53) at day 180 by FLACS compared with 0.43 D (95% CI 0.36 to 0.51) at day 40 (p=0.95) and 0.46 D (95% CI 0.37 to 0.52) at day 180 (p=0.91) with CPS. ECL was significantly lower in FLACS compared with CPS at both day 40 and day 180. ECL was correlated to the energy used. We found no difference in refractive predictability or CDVA between the groups. &quot;</field>
</doc>
</add>