<add>
<doc>
<field name="id">86</field>
<field name="content">Changes in peripheral blood T-cell balance after percutaneous tumor ablation.,"Painful osseous metastases are a common problem in patients with malignancy, and they can be associated with significant morbidity owing to immobility, pain, pathologic fracture, or neurovascular compromise or all of these. We retrospectively evaluated pain levels and tumor enhancement in patients who underwent palliative percutaneous cryoablation for painful bone metastasis. In this institutional review board-approved, health insurance portability and accountability act-compliant study, we retrospectively searched our departments picture archiving system for patients who underwent computed tomography (CT)-guided percutaneous cryoablation for treatment of painful metastatic osseous disease over a 6-year period (1/1/2005-12/31/2011). The preprocedure and postprocedure images and imaging reports, primary tumor type, CT-guided cryoablation procedure details, treated tumor response, immediate and 3-month postprocedure complications, reported pain response to cryoablation, postprocedural tumor imaging characteristics, and imaging response of noncryoablated systemically treated metastatic lesions were reviewed in patients with metastatic osseous disease who underwent cryoablation. All 16 patients reported improvement in pain within 1 week after the procedure and at 3-month clinical follow-up. A total of 6.2% had tumor growth and 93.8% had tumor arrest or shrinkage on follow-up CT, although all study patients had progression of noncryoablated metastases at other sites despite systemic therapy. A total of 62.5% of patients with posttreatment contrasted CT demonstrated marginal enhancement at the ablation site, although only single patient had interval growth. Most of our patients had tumor arrest or shrinkage on follow-up imaging, despite progression of noncryoablated metastases treated with preprocedure and postprocedure systemic therapy. Radiation therapy, chemotherapy, and analgesics have a moderate failure rate and require repeat treatments where quality of life is the foremost objective. CT-guided cryoablation is a safe palliative treatment to reduce pain in patients with painful osseous metastatic disease, achieve effective local tumor control, and in some cases, provide a curative option for a target lesion."
</field>
</doc>
</add>